<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed</title>
    <link>https://www.newagebd.net</link>
    <description>Daily Feed - New Age BD</description>
    <item>
      <title>Arguments in Abu Sayed killing case Jan 20</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/288202/arguments-in-abu-sayed-killing-case-jan-20</link>
      <description>The International Crimes Tribunal-2 on Wednesday set January 20 for placing arguments in the crimes against humanity case filed over the killing of Begum Rokeya University, Rangpur student Abu Sayed during the July mass uprising......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/56e8c500b2ae1f2c7e7306784a729f34_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Denmark to boost military presence in Greenland from today</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/europe/288201/denmark-to-boost-military-presence-in-greenland-from-today</link>
      <description>Denmark will beef up its military presence in Greenland ‘from today’, the defence ministry said Wednesday, just before high-stakes talks were to start in Washington over US president Donald Trump’s threats to take over the Arctic island......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/c92b6ff741861aaf15f148baf309ba3a_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SC rejects Cumilla-4 BNP candidate’s plea on loan status</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/288200/sc-rejects-cumilla-4-bnp-candidates-plea-on-loan-status</link>
      <description>The Appellate Division on Wednesday rejected an application filed by Cumilla-4 BNP candidate Manzurul Ahsan Munshi seeking to lift its earlier stay on a High Court decision that asked the authorities not to include his name on the list of loan defaulters......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/05d1a30ef634825fa130633a455a5306_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran threatens to strike US bases if attacked</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/middle-east/288199/iran-threatens-to-strike-us-bases-if-attacked</link>
      <description>A senior adviser to Iran’s supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei warned president Donald Trump on Wednesday that an Iranian strike in June on an American base in Qatar had demonstrated its ability to respond to any attack......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/48f9237ea681c6b98085b0743fb9c762_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SC ends 2-decade legal saga, terms case ‘judicial tyranny’</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/288198/sc-ends-2-decade-legal-saga-terms-case-judicial-tyranny</link>
      <description>The Appellate Division has ended a two-decade legal saga involving the service status of 988 National University employees appointed between 2003 and 2004, when the Bangladesh Nationalist Party–led alliance was in power......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/e62dd978ad675f4bbd900a6ca061009e_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Political will for increasing women’s participation urged</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/elections/288197/political-will-for-increasing-womens-participation-urged</link>
      <description>Politicians, academics and professionals on Wednesday at a dialogue expressed concern over the participation of fewer number of women in politics of Bangladesh and said that political will was crucial to increasing women’s participation in the area......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/83dd18b86f49853b3237a11254306fcc_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flats for FFs occupied by others: welfare assoc</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/288196/flats-for-ffs-occupied-by-others-welfare-assoc</link>
      <description>Of the 870 flats meant for impoverished freedom fighters at the Bijoy Rakeen City housing project, 766 are occupied by influential individuals who did not participate in the War of Independence, alleged freedom fighter Abu Md Ishtiaq Aziz Ulfat, administrator of the Muktijoddha O Muktijoddha Poribar Kalyan Samiti, a welfare association, on Wednesday......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/41b9cc6701cb1302a4bb5294d181b204_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BNP demands fresh postal ballot</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/elections/288195/bnp-demands-fresh-postal-ballot</link>
      <description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party’s central election steering committee on Wednesday alleged that a political party was attempting to manipulate the upcoming Jatiya Sangsad elections by luring marginalised voters with money transfers through bKash and collecting copies of national identity cards......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/ea4d04e316aceec3c27406aa7febce4c_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CWAB threatens boycott demanding Najmul’s resignation</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/Cricket/288194/cwab-threatens-boycott-demanding-najmuls-resignation</link>
      <description>The Cricketers Welfare Association of Bangladesh on Wednesday announced a boycott of all cricket if the BCB board director M Najmul Islam doesn’t resign before the first match of the Bangladesh Premier League on Thursday. 

...</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/abafa9795bced20e38e3b33f3de84cf8_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bancharampur UNO Ferdous Ara dies</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/288192/bancharampur-uno-ferdous-ara-dies</link>
      <description>Ferdous Ara, upazila nirbahi officer of Bancharampur upazila in Brahmanbaria, died on Wednesday at a hospital in Dhaka......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elderly patient dies as local operators obstruct ambulance to Dhaka</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/288191/elderly-patient-dies-as-local-operators-obstruct-ambulance-to-dhaka</link>
      <description>An elderly patient died inside an ambulance on Tuesday night after some local ambulance operators allegedly obstructed his transfer to Dhaka at multiple points in Shariatpur......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tejgaon College students block Farmgate again for justice</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/288190/tejgaon-college-students-block-farmgate-again-for-justice</link>
      <description>Students of Tejgaon College on Wednesday once again blocked the Farmgate crossing in the capital Dhaka for about five hours, demanding the arrest of and exemplary punishment for those responsible for the death of their fellow student after a clash, causing immense sufferings to city commuters......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Right message, wrong messengers</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/288149/right-message-wrong-messengers</link>
      <description>MULTIPLE things can be true at once. The Iranian people are engaged in a legitimate popular struggle against an entrenched political elite that has failed to meet their material needs and has answered demands for freedom and dignity with unconscionable violence and repression. At the same time, the US has no political, legal or moral basis to intervene in Iran. The dire......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/8dc17ab664fc652b25abaf092986aa3d_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI in job market</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/288147/ai-in-job-market</link>
      <description>ARTIFICIAL intelligence has entered people’s daily lives in such a way that the moment of shaping the future from fantasy to reality has remained unknown to many. It is currently used in office software, industrial machinery, medical image analysis and job application selection. The tasks that used to take a lot of people’s time are now being done automatically. The result......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/2413eb8eae6746d9fcd43116c0c2b907_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polygamy: betrayal of women</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/288146/polygamy-betrayal-of-women</link>
      <description>RECENT headlines — wife’s approval no longer essential for second marriage — are not only media hype. They reflect the profoundly worrying path of a High Court ruling. The court upheld Section 6 of the Muslim Family Laws Ordinance 1961 and made it clear that a Muslim man’s second marriage does not depend on his first wife’s agreement......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/4bafcb3ee8eaaf70cdb1efd8d50f1346_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bangladesh’s governance challenges</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/288145/bangladeshs-governance-challenges</link>
      <description>GOVERNANCE in South Asia has been closely examined in recent decades because of the region’s complex mix of political, economic, social and security challenges. Despite advances in democratic expansion and economic growth, the region still faces governance issues that erode public trust, hinder inclusive development and heighten social vulnerabilities. Bangladesh......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/eb1d4577552527433db11f0fb2ecd325_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Custodial death raises alarm for accountability</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/editorial/288144/custodial-death-raises-alarm-for-accountability</link>
      <description>THE death of a Bangladesh Nationalist Party leader in the custody of joint forces in Chuadanga early January 13 is unacceptable. The joint forces in a raid on an area at Jibannagar detained the general secretary of the party’s Jibannagar municipal unit at about 11:00pm late January 12 on charges of keeping an illegal firearm. After an arms recovery drive, as official accounts......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/6ba76cddd885cd72d48195275688f4d0_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EC has issues to address to ensure fair election</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/editorial/288143/ec-has-issues-to-address-to-ensure-fair-election</link>
      <description>WITH less than a month to go before the national elections scheduled for February 12, the credibility of the electoral process will hinge not on official assurances but on visible, consistent and impartial action by the Election Commission. While the government has repeatedly promised free and fair elections, the growing list of complaints from political parties suggests......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/8065da6ebbbae7b96105f0669056ee41_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EC approves 73 more appeals on 5th day</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/elections/288222/ec-approves-73-more-appeals-on-5th-day</link>
      <description>The election commission on Wednesday approved 73 more appeals on the fifth day against the order of acceptance and cancellation of nomination papers of the returning officers in the forthcoming 13th national elections......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/a3655ee000a7cf0ef5788543ca027c08_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Old cases overshadowed by new ones: probe</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/288221/old-cases-overshadowed-by-new-ones-probe</link>
      <description>The Commission of Inquiry on Enforced Disappearances in its final report said that the cases of forced disappearances were quickly overshadowed by fresh surges of enforced disappearances, particularly heightened during politically volatile periods, such as national elections and opposition mobilisations......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/8058297182c5f8d8cb7e0952c48cd1d1_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On-arrival visa suspended to avert risks before polls: Touhid</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/288220/on-arrival-visa-suspended-to-avert-risks-before-polls-touhid</link>
      <description>The Bangladesh government has issued a set of guidelines restricting the issuance of the on-arrival visa facility between January 15 and February 15 to avoid ‘any unwanted situation’ ahead of the upcoming general election scheduled for February 12......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/346ec0ee03d7a2ed31d7fffa800a7a6d_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More migrants are dying in ICE detention under Trump: data</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/north-america/288219/more-migrants-are-dying-in-ice-detention-under-trump-data</link>
      <description>The confrontation tactics used by US Immigration and Customs Enforcement have been in the spotlight since the fatal shooting of protester Renee Nicole Good in Minneapolis, Minnesota, on January 7......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/42930c787c76a034db8f35ec7900ae1b_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israel kills six in Gaza despite ceasefire</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/middle-east/288218/israel-kills-six-in-gaza-despite-ceasefire</link>
      <description>The Israeli military said Wednesday it had killed six ‘militants’ in an updated toll from an exchange of fire in Gaza the day before, accusing them of violating the ceasefire in the territory......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/7a7c4c3df1e92cd3612bd030b441356f_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICJ genocide case flawed and unfounded: Myanmar govt</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/south-asia/288217/icj-genocide-case-flawed-and-unfounded-myanmar-govt</link>
      <description>An international court case alleging Myanmar committed genocide against the mostly Muslim Rohingya minority is ‘flawed and unfounded’, Yangon’s foreign ministry said Wednesday......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/23100756e8a4dfbe7633b794a9ff0b16_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uphold force’s image: adviser asks new BGB recruits</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/288216/uphold-forces-image-adviser-asks-new-bgb-recruits</link>
      <description>Home adviser retired Lieutenant General Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Wednesday called on newly recruited Border Guard Bangladesh members to uphold the force’s image by embodying discipline, professionalism and the core values of the organisation......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/5637244f89e1c0a33c983ce897c8be23_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Journalist Manik Saha’s 22nd death anniv today</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/288215/journalist-manik-sahas-22nd-death-anniv-today</link>
      <description>The 22nd anniversary of the death of Manik Chandra Saha, a freedom fighter and Ekushey Padak-winning journalist, will be observed today......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/d3cab66609325fdc2f47787cf4eabcf0_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dockyard security guard stabbed dead in Keraniganj</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/288214/dockyard-security-guard-stabbed-dead-in-keraniganj</link>
      <description>A dockyard security guard was stabbed to death allegedly  by muggers in  Bashundhara River View Balur Math area of South Keraniganj early Wednesday......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/e1a4f575fffeadf9a6fdee0cb1adc77b_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RU staff stage protests for safe workplace</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/288213/ru-staff-stage-protests-for-safe-workplace</link>
      <description>A group of officers and employees of Rajshahi University on Wednesday formed a human chain demanding a safe and secure working environment on the campus......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/b8971c537b97c7896e8b9b397c1c25fd_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EC clarifies postal ballots’ viral video in Bahrain</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/288212/ec-clarifies-postal-ballots-viral-video-in-bahrain</link>
      <description>The election commission on Wednesday clarified a viral video showing a large number of postal ballots delivered to a single address in Bahrain, saying that the incident resulted from differences in the country’s postal delivery system and did not involve any irregularities in the voting process......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/8e9da244aa85ce3684946464fd78a0ee_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selim Al Deen’s 18th death anniversary observed</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/theatre/288211/selim-al-deens-18th-death-anniversary-observed</link>
      <description>Theatre troupes and cultural organisations observed the 18th anniversary of death of legendary playwright Selim Al Deen on Wednesday with seminars, processions and commemorative programmes at multiple venues......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/862ee11cae22854c586d81f88ff684ba_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SEC students continue protest demanding SUST affiliation</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/campus-bites/288210/sec-students-continue-protest-demanding-sust-affiliation</link>
      <description>Sylhet Engineering College students have been observing a shutdown programme on the campus in demand of incorporating the college as an institute under the Shahjalal University of Science and Technology......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/b799e9d5ec034caa385bb8047726887a_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DU statistics dept welcomes freshers</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/campus-bites/288209/du-statistics-dept-welcomes-freshers</link>
      <description>The department of statistics at Dhaka University held its freshers’ reception for first-year undergraduate students of the 2024–2025 academic session on Wednesday at the TSC auditorium on the campus......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/c9744f23a3c4e9582c20e4ff3d397ae8_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BUFT National Career Fest 2026 held</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/campus-bites/288208/buft-national-career-fest-2026-held</link>
      <description>BGMEA University of Fashion and Technology, through its Career Development Club, organised the BUFT National Career Fest 2026 on January 14–15 on its permanent campus at Turag in Dhaka......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/6d3eb50d746a9313a70f07e7d62c3ca7_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BMU launches e-logbook in postgrad residency prog</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/campus-bites/288207/bmu-launches-e-logbook-in-postgrad-residency-prog</link>
      <description>Bangladesh Medical University has introduced e-logbooks in its postgraduate residency programme, beginning with five departments in a pilot phase......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/882818c2591cb55daae5c3a39f6330bf_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ACC files 12 cases against PK Halder, 35 others</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/288206/acc-files-12-cases-against-pk-halder-35-others</link>
      <description>The Anti-Corruption Commission has filed 12 separate cases against Prashanta Kumar Halder and 35 others on charges of embezzling Tk 5.31 billion by taking loans from FAS Finance and Investment Limited in the names of various fictitious companies......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/34b3211a3962dad02a0a744f0c9a8575_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ctg tribunal sets January 19 for charge hearing</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/288205/ctg-tribunal-sets-january-19-for-charge-hearing</link>
      <description>A Chattogram Divisional Speedy Trial Tribunal on Wednesday set January 19 for holding the hearing on charge framing against 39 accused, including former ISKCON organiser Chinmoy Krishna Das Brahmachari, in the murder case of lawyer Saiful Islam Alif......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/afb57bd4f2d000fc25bc378e7c8f34ec_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BCG arrests 2 with 75,000 Yaba pills in Teknaf</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/288204/bcg-arrests-2-with-75000-yaba-pills-in-teknaf</link>
      <description>The Bangladesh Coast Guard arrested two alleged drug traffickers with 75,000 yaba pills in Teknaf of Cox’s Bazar on Tuesday......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/369f0acef341b1ce9287ba9b73c11e88_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Painter electrocuted in Dhaka</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/288203/painter-electrocuted-in-dhaka</link>
      <description>A 35-year-old painter electrocuted while working on a four-story building in Adabar area of Dhaka on Wednesday......</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/47271ee96d83716e1a08d2d8e2260106_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
