<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed</title>
    <link>https://www.newagebd.net</link>
    <description>Daily Feed - New Age BD</description>
    <item>
      <title>Jamaat says nothing about 1971 role</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/285329/jamaat-says-nothing-about-1971-role</link>
      <description>The leaders of Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami on Monday at a discussion vowed to build a corruption-free democratic country if they were voted to power in the elections slated for February 12 next year....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CU admin building locked for pro-VC’s resignation</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/285328/cu-admin-building-locked-for-pro-vcs-resignation</link>
      <description>Several student organisations at Chittagong University on Monday locked the administrative building, demanding the resignation of pro-vice-chancellor (academic) Professor Mohammad Shamim Uddin Khan over his remarks about the 1971 killings of martyred intellectuals....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidency University holds CSE Fest 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/285327/presidency-university-holds-cse-fest-2025</link>
      <description>Presidency University has recently held a CSE Fest 2025 on the university campus in Dhaka....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/d4b7b03aaa48347f1b147f6c9f1efdc0_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chevron extends artificial limb support in Sylhet</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/285326/chevron-extends-artificial-limb-support-in-sylhet</link>
      <description>The SMILE project of Chevron, in collaboration with the Jalalabad Disabled Rehab Centre and Hospital (JDRCH), celebrated the closing ceremony of the Restoring Mobility: Artificial Limb Support intervention at Grand Sylhet....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/87a2e8ffada14f37e9a2330cbf6c8bd8_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Liberation War ideals yet to materialise</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/285325/liberation-war-ideals-yet-to-materialise</link>
      <description>Political leaders, intellectuals, economists, and rights defenders have said that the core ideals of the Liberation War— equality, human dignity, social justice and a discrimination-free democratic state —have not been established in Bangladesh even after 54 years of the independence....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/d215749ec592da7a433d867d3576e026_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Victory Day today</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/285324/victory-day-today</link>
      <description>The nation celebrates the 55th Victory Day, remembering the heroic and supreme sacrifices of freedom fighters to free the country from the marauding Pakistani military in the War of Independence on December 16, 1971....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/d5d5fceadda4cb0720474f530ef6f617_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indigenous freedom fighters of the Chittagong Hill Tracts</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/285301/indigenous-freedom-fighters-of-the-chittagong-hill-tracts</link>
      <description>THE Memorial Volume Honouring Titled Freedom Fighters (Janata Bank Limited, 2012) documents the lives of the heroes of 1971, including UK Ching, a distinguished freedom fighter from the Chittagong Hill Tracts. Alongside UK Ching, who was awarded the Bir Bikrom gallantry title, many other Indigenous fighters from the hill regions displayed exceptional courage during Bangladesh’s Liberation War......</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/caf0e513d5bd655b7329ddaa2eb26e6c_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The unfinished promise of victory</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/285300/the-unfinished-promise-of-victory</link>
      <description>BANGLADESH is no longer an object of anyone’s neglect. Half a century ago, the world looked upon this land through a mixture of pity and predicted failure, as if the newly liberated nation were destined to remain buried beneath the rubble left by genocide, famine, poverty and structural destruction. Today, when Bangladesh celebrates Victory Day, it stands among......</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/cc8f9ba2600761af22d99bce67880264_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Loving a country that keeps breaking your heart</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/285299/loving-a-country-that-keeps-breaking-your-heart</link>
      <description>BANGLADESH is not for beginners. Even the memes tell you that. Step outside, and chaos meets you immediately — traffic snarls, honking horns, voices screaming, endless crowds colliding in every direction. Every day demands stamina, attention, presence. It is exhausting, infuriating, relentless. People argue endlessly. Intolerance simmers quietly in corners. Ideas that are not immediately practical are dismissed. Questioning......</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/e0b08a2a142db61c4aa0e8bfb3583a13_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where do we stand at 54?</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/285298/where-do-we-stand-at-54</link>
      <description>THIS soil of ours has witnessed agitation, bloodshed, death and pledges to build the nation anew since 1947. The fairest of the demand was turned down; the most vibrant voices were silenced along with the chanters, drenched in gore, the most celebratory moments blackened by treachery. Thus, this nation, liberated from a discriminatory rule for 23 years in 1971......</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/5f5884ba95a0e3f36e8c8957c7dcad89_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interim govt falters on reform delivery</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/editorial/285297/interim-govt-falters-on-reform-delivery</link>
      <description>THE observations of the heads and members of the commissions that the interim government set up to effect reforms in state governance, noting that the expected reforms have not come about despite people’s aspirations because of bureaucratic resistance and the unwillingness of certain quarters opposed to reforms, including some political parties, are points to ponder......</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/5b9e3bf414895d44679919393df6f8cb_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Right-wing war talk resembles that of India, Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/editorial/285296/right-wing-war-talk-resembles-that-of-india-pakistan</link>
      <description>BANGLADESH celebrates its 54th anniversary of national independence today, the most significant day in the collective history of the Bangladeshis, for it was on this day that Bangladesh was born through a bloodied people’s war against the occupation forces of the erstwhile Pakistan in March 1971. The war began immediately after the Pakistan’s West-based......</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/2f3d2161ec6016467583e6daf2be18d8_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
