<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed</title>
    <link>https://www.newagebd.net</link>
    <description>Daily Feed - New Age BD</description>
    <item>
      <title>City fight back to end Anfield hoodoo</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/football/290639/city-fight-back-to-end-anfield-hoodoo</link>
      <description>Erling Haaland's stoppage-time penalty earned Manchester City a dramatic 2-1 win at Liverpool on Sunday to reduce Arsenal's lead at the top of the Premier League back to six points.

...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/016a357e5335eb33b552436d77f996a9_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sylhet OC accused of bias</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/290638/sylhet-oc-accused-of-bias</link>
      <description>Rezaul Hasan Kayes Lodi, chief election agent of BNP-nominated candidate Khandaker Abdul Muktadir for Sylhet-1 (city and sadar upazila) constituency, accused Biman Bandar police station officer-in-charge of bias....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bangladesh, UK sign survey vessel purchase deal</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/foreign-affairs/290637/bangladesh-uk-sign-survey-vessel-purchase-deal</link>
      <description>A government-to-government contract for the purchase of hydrographic and oceanographic survey ship ‘HMS Enterprise’ was signed between Bangladesh and the United Kingdom at the Bangladesh Navy headquarters in Dhaka on Sunday....Bangladesh cultural tours</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Court freezes ex-MP Rubina, husband, ex-secy Shahid’s accounts</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/290636/court-freezes-ex-mp-rubina-husband-ex-secy-shahids-accounts</link>
      <description>A Dhaka court on Sunday ordered the freezing of two bank accounts of former lawmaker Syeda Rubina Akter, one of her husband Md Mosharraf Hossain Sardar and four accounts belonging to former LGRD secretary Abu Alam Md Shahid Khan....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NCP’s Akhtar gets death threat, files GD</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/290635/ncps-akhtar-gets-death-threat-files-gd</link>
      <description>Akhtar Hossain, member secretary of National Citizens’ Party and the 11-party alliance candidate for Rangpur-4 constituency, has received a death threat, according to a general diary filed with Pirgacha police station....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>321 publishers to boycott Ekushey Book Fair in Ramadan</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/literature/290634/321-publishers-to-boycott-ekushey-book-fair-in-ramadan</link>
      <description>A group of publishers have said that they will boycott the forthcoming Amar Ekushey book fair 2026 if it is held during the fasting month of Ramadan....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Education law unlikely during interim govt</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/education/290633/education-law-unlikely-during-interim-govt</link>
      <description>The draft Education Act, 2026, which was uploaded on the education ministry web site past week for public opinions, has received 667 suggestions from people of different groups, said education ministry officials....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Govt withdraws 23,865 political cases</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/290631/govt-withdraws-23865-political-cases</link>
      <description>The interim government has withdrawn 23,865 false and politically motivated cases filed by the previous Awami League government against leaders and activists of various political parties,  including BNP, Jamaat-e-Islami and Hefazat-e-Islam....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kamindu heroics steer Sri Lanka past Ireland in T20 World Cup</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/cricket/290632/kamindu-heroics-steer-sri-lanka-past-ireland-in-t20-world-cup</link>
      <description>Sri Lanka's 11th-hour call to draft in Kamindu Mendis proved a masterstroke as the all-rounder produced a match turning cameo to set up a 20-run win over Ireland in their T20 World Cup opener at Colombo’s R. Premadasa Stadium on Sunday.

...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/2f3ad9b95a5bcf43459e214b16d6ae57_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nahid vows social justice, economic fairness</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/290630/nahid-vows-social-justice-economic-fairness</link>
      <description>National Citizen Party convener Nahid Islam, in a televised address Sunday evening, outlined a sweeping reform agenda emphasising social justice, economic fairness and  accountable governance while sharply criticizing past governments for discrimination and neglect....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/3dc0b13fc3baa405f7b4c610bf3483a0_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We will safeguard people’s rights, dignity: Jamaat</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/290629/we-will-safeguard-peoples-rights-dignity-jamaat</link>
      <description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami amir Shafiqur Rahman on Sunday said that they would act as guardians of the people’s lives, wealth and dignity, declaring they would serve the nation rather than rule it....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/3a2e19dbb21c92914cc7629c1d2bcd5a_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CGS survey: 50pc minority voters worry about security</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/290628/cgs-survey-50pc-minority-voters-worry-about-security</link>
      <description>More than 50 per cent of the minority communities are concerned about security ahead of the 13th Jatiya Sangsad elections, while over 25 per cent consider the voting process unsafe or extremely unsafe, according to a survey by the Centre for Governance Studies....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/4f80e669a54a1c4f1f652ef580723580_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bangladesh-US tariff deal likely today</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/foreign-affairs/290627/bangladesh-us-tariff-deal-likely-today</link>
      <description>Bangladesh eyes further cut in the rate of United States-imposed reciprocal tariff as the country is set to sign a deal with the US today in Washington amid purchasing more US goods....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/1065a5892a26aea2c9e18a0b76da92c7_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polls violence on amid weak regulation: TIB</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/290626/polls-violence-on-amid-weak-regulation-tib</link>
      <description>Briefing on the pre-election situation, the Transparency International Bangladesh on Sunday said that most political parties and their candidates contesting the 13th Jatiya Sangsad elections continued old-style violent politics....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/0e23f1600f57bf3cff90088b5b3c4262_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hamas leader rejects disarmament or ‘foreign rule’</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/middle-east/290625/hamas-leader-rejects-disarmament-or-foreign-rule</link>
      <description>A senior Hamas leader said Sunday that the Palestinian Islamist movement would not surrender its weapons nor accept foreign intervention in Gaza, pushing back against US and Israeli demands....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AB Party pledges just society based on Liberation War, uprising</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/290624/ab-party-pledges-just-society-based-on-liberation-war-uprising</link>
      <description>The Amar Bangladesh Party on Sunday pledged the formation of a just society based on the spirit of the 1971 liberation war and the 2024 July Uprising....Bangladesh cultural tours</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Govt rejects TIB claim over election-related killings</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/290623/govt-rejects-tib-claim-over-election-related-killings</link>
      <description>The interim government on Sunday rejected Transparency International Bangladesh’s claim over the number of election-related killings ahead of the next Jatiya Sangsad elections scheduled for February 12....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/f4c129f6884c1ac5a8d492911a526648_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Govt under fire for hasty, hazy foreign deals</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/290622/govt-under-fire-for-hasty-hazy-foreign-deals</link>
      <description>The interim government led by Nobel laureate Professor Muhammad Yunus has been signing agreements and memorandums of understanding one after another with foreign countries even at the fag end of its tenure amid widespread criticisms from important quarters......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/165811d8195b5c2f4a55c259ed7997ab_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why human factors engineering matters</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/290621/why-human-factors-engineering-matters</link>
      <description>Human Factors Engineering, also known as ergonomics, is the scientific study of how humans interact with systems. It draws on psychology, engineering, design and organisational studies to enhance safety, efficiency and well-being, ensuring that tools, technologies and workplaces align with human abilities and limitations......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/0345931c759f29b8104fd420fd9872ac_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can manifesto deliver long-awaited change?</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/290619/can-manifesto-deliver-long-awaited-change</link>
      <description>ELECTION season in Bangladesh is always a time of hope, expectation and promise. The manifestos roll out with fanfare, each one more grandiose than the last, as political parties strive to offer a better future to the people. Yet, more often than not, these promises remain nothing more than a distant dream. They are like clouds on the horizon, always promising rain but......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/922fa6fc01a6916206240059537eea37_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When diplomacy meets ballot box</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/290617/when-diplomacy-meets-ballot-box</link>
      <description>WHENEVER a new US ambassador arrives in Dhaka, a familiar cycle begins. Optimism appears in some quarters. Suspicion hardens in others. Expectations, often exaggerated, are projected onto one individual. Yet ambassadors are never just individuals. They arrive carrying the weight of their country’s foreign policy, shaped by history, geopolitics and the local......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/3708de30ac7fe6fd2e83a0a4d04138a4_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wetlands are treasure islands</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/290614/wetlands-are-treasure-islands</link>
      <description>BANGLADESH is a delta, crisscrossed by an intricate network of rivers, haors, baors, lakes, beels, mangrove and swamp forests, ponds, dighis, estuaries, and floodplains. Our wetlands are not static backwaters; they are dynamic ecosystems that sustain life in ways both visible and unseen. According to the Ramsar Convention, nearly two-thirds of Bangladesh is classified as......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/faf728865138be0488f323023d11c6aa_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ballot authentication can stem tempering with voting</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/editorial/290613/ballot-authentication-can-stem-tempering-with-voting</link>
      <description>WITH three days to go before the national elections for a democratic transition after years of disenfranchisement, it is imperative that the vote be conducted without electoral fraud. In this context, the concerns that the Bangladesh Nationalist Party raised on February 7 that a political party was planning on ways for election manipulation need serious consideration. The......Bangladesh cultural tours</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/4e906b60dd21bca357be6e3be95c9b4a_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Candidate’s tax secrecy clouds election accountability</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/editorial/290612/candidates-tax-secrecy-clouds-election-accountability</link>
      <description>MORE than a third of the 2,026 candidates contesting the forthcoming national elections, scheduled for February 12, have not made their income tax records public when they filed their nomination, as Citizens for Good Governance reported on February 7. The electoral legislation makes it mandatory that the candidates submit the proof of filing income tax returns. The......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/85b73f4d9bb0eb445b7a449edbb0f736_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
