<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed</title>
    <link>https://www.newagebd.net</link>
    <description>Daily Feed - New Age BD</description>
    <item>
      <title>Disallowed parties’ absence won’t affect inclusivity: BNP</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/287213/disallowed-parties-absence-wont-affect-inclusivity-bnp</link>
      <description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party election steering committee chair Nazrul Islam Khan on Sunday said that the political parties banned or restricted under existing laws due to public outrage lack the legal right to contest elections....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/08ac50fed7de85b472948ebde8f1a649_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cold wave sweeping over 7 dists, Dhaka temp to remain same</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/287212/cold-wave-sweeping-over-7-dists-dhaka-temp-to-remain-same</link>
      <description>A mild cold wave is sweeping over seven districts that will continue for the next five days with the possibility of intensifying cold, while Dhaka temperatures may remain unchanged....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/8a9ca22b30fa8c9230becd5ca84dc86c_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15pc textbooks yet to be distributed</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/education/287211/15pc-textbooks-yet-to-be-distributed</link>
      <description>The National Curriculum and Textbook Board on Sunday said that about 84.78 per cent of all free textbooks for the 2026 academic year have been distributed till Saturday....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/4380c797bd0877d2b7d470f575fd040a_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>North Canvas celebrates New Year</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/photography-art-design/287210/north-canvas-celebrates-new-year</link>
      <description>Visual artist’s organisation North Canvas Bangladesh organised a five-day group art exhibition titled New Year Art Expo, which is currently under way at Priyo Bangla Art Gallery of Banglamotor in Dhaka. ...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/3c01e6a54eaea0c677aa575394eca4ae_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Increase in budget allocation for health sector demanded</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/287209/increase-in-budget-allocation-for-health-sector-demanded</link>
      <description>Speakers at a programme at the Bangladesh Medical University in Dhaka on Sunday demanded an increase in budget allocation for the health sector in Bangladesh. ...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/4f774334c721799066b8d0db8c58fcd7_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US oil firms to head into Venezuela: Trump</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/latin-america/287208/us-oil-firms-to-head-into-venezuela-trump</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump said on Saturday he would allow American oil companies to go into Venezuela to tap its massive crude reserves after a US military operation seized its leader Nicolas Maduro....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/b4186ee38e621e5caf75cb99de57a2d0_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICT prosecution seeks trial of ex-NTMC chief Ziaul Ahsan</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/287207/ict-prosecution-seeks-trial-of-ex-ntmc-chief-ziaul-ahsan</link>
      <description>The International Crimes Tribunal’s prosecution has sought to begin the trial of retired major general Ziaul Ahsan, former director general of the National Telecommunication Monitoring Center, by framing charges over his alleged involvement in enforced disappearances and......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/5c3497dd999a854c82b4da44520e235a_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wives outpace husbands in asset holdings</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/287206/wives-outpace-husbands-in-asset-holdings</link>
      <description>The affidavits submitted by the candidates for the 13th Jatiya Sangsad elections show that many wives of contenders own significantly more assets than their husbands, raising questions about the sources of wealth and transparency in political and election financing....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/31592926638dba1bce40191f11640dc5_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarique seeks private sector cooperation to address economic challenges</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/287205/tarique-seeks-private-sector-cooperation-to-address-economic-challenges</link>
      <description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party acting chair Tarique Rahman on Sunday said that his party was closely examining key economic and governance challenges raised by business leaders, including the law and order, banking sector distress, and energy shortages....Political party merchandise</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/4d0a2e5773d24f22e55fcb9d6bea445f_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Violence thrives where justice hesitates</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/287169/violence-thrives-where-justice-hesitates</link>
      <description>LAW is often described as society’s last shelter. Justice is supposed to be the thin line that separates order from chaos, authority from arbitrariness and power from violence. Yet the latest report by the Human Rights Culture Foundation reads less like a legal audit and more like a forensic record of how that shelter has developed cracks large enough for fear to walk......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/f4ddc14b9a6639e63ff031f4f296bfba_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2026 will test cyber defences</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/287168/2026-will-test-cyber-defences</link>
      <description>The world has stepped into 2026 with a digital tension felt across boardrooms, data centres and living rooms alike. We have never been more connected, yet never more exposed. Cyberattacks no longer feel like distant headlines but like storms already forming on the horizon, capable of sweeping across countries and industries within hours. A breach anywhere......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/4276dbff1d8371afba31b3e9333f9626_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cooking gas held hostage by cartels</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/287166/cooking-gas-held-hostage-by-cartels</link>
      <description>THERE are shortages born of nature and markets, and then there are shortages manufactured by human design. Bangladesh’s ongoing liquefied petroleum gas crisis belongs firmly to the second category. For nearly two weeks, LPG cylinders have vanished from large swathes of the country. Where they are available, a government-fixed price of Tk 1,253 for a 12-kilogram......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/f46a55ebb87731827b756bdd7aabda5a_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Illegal, immoral, dangerous</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/287165/illegal-immoral-dangerous</link>
      <description>THE recent US military strikes in Venezuela and the arrest of President Nicolás Maduro did not come out of nowhere. They were the result of years of tension, sanctions and political confrontation between Washington and Caracas. For the United States, Maduro has long been viewed not as a legitimate head of state but as the leader of a criminal regime. This......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/8ad4aaf78eb2adc98e6733fc87470968_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Death of int’l law in plain sight</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/287164/death-of-intl-law-in-plain-sight</link>
      <description>WHAT the United States is signalling in Venezuela is not merely a dispute over one government, one election, or one leader. It is a warning to the world that international law — already fragile, already selectively enforced — has now been openly pushed aside. And this warning comes from a man who presents himself as a global peacemaker, a would-be Nobel laureate......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/8be0bde04d5443f2ff90455b63809529_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US assault on Venezuela shreds global norms</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/editorial/287163/us-assault-on-venezuela-shreds-global-norms</link>
      <description>THE United States strike against Venezuela on December 3 and the capture of its president Nicolás Maduro and his wife Cilia Flores are an odious act in the modern-day rules-based order. The Delta Force of the US army bombed Caracas and snatched Maduro and his wife in what the Trump administration says has been done in conjunction with the US Law Enforcement for......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/8fba855a3c80beb3a9bb5c837db41cbb_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time for firmer response to BSF’s border violence</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/editorial/287162/time-for-firmer-response-to-bsfs-border-violence</link>
      <description>THE latest figures on border violence by Indian border guards expose an upsetting continuity that renders repeated assurances from New Delhi hollow. Ain O Salish Kendra’s annual rights report says that at least 34 Bangladeshis were killed by India’s Border Security Force in 2025, the highest in five years. Besides, Indians killed at least 12 more along the frontiers in Sylhet......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/ad791d1a546aba49613147448c3bf853_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man shot dead at Padma char in Natore</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/287224/man-shot-dead-at-padma-char-in-natore</link>
      <description>A man was shot dead inside his bedroom on the Padma River char area at Lalpur upazila in Natore early Sunday....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 03:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BUFT holds cultural festival</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/287223/buft-holds-cultural-festival</link>
      <description>The cultural club of BGMEA University of Fashion and Technology held a national cultural festival at the BUFT in Dhaka on Sunday....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 03:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>114 killed in week of attacks in Sudan’s Darfur</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/africa/287222/114-killed-in-week-of-attacks-in-sudans-darfur</link>
      <description>Attacks by Sudan’s army and its paramilitary foes on two towns in the western Darfur region over the past week have killed 114 people, medical sources said Sunday....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 03:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Myanmar junta frees hundreds of prisoners</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/south-asia/287221/myanmar-junta-frees-hundreds-of-prisoners</link>
      <description>Hundreds of prisoners walked free in Myanmar on Sunday after the junta announced annual independence day pardons, just a week after the start of an election that international monitors have denounced as sham....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 03:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ACC sues National Bank ex-MD, 25 others for loan scam</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/287220/acc-sues-national-bank-ex-md-25-others-for-loan-scam</link>
      <description>The Anti-Corruption Commission has filed a case against 26 people, including National Bank’s former managing director, on charges of embezzling over Tk 903.67 crore. ...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 03:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarique to be appointed BNP chair in a day or two: Fakhrul</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/287219/tarique-to-be-appointed-bnp-chair-in-a-day-or-two-fakhrul</link>
      <description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party secretary general Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Sunday said that BNP acting chair Tarique Rahman would be appointed the party’s chair within a day or two....Political party merchandise</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 01:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/e1555621847dae8b3a4b9850a93bca85_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police asked to uphold neutrality in election duties</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/287218/police-asked-to-uphold-neutrality-in-election-duties</link>
      <description>Home adviser retired Lieutenant General Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury called on all members of the police force to perform their election-related duties with the highest standards of responsibility, integrity and professionalism....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 01:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RAB intensifies hunt for Hadi murder suspects</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/287217/rab-intensifies-hunt-for-hadi-murder-suspects</link>
      <description>The Rapid Action Battalion has stepped up efforts to arrest the two prime suspects directly linked to the killing of Inquilab Mancha spokesperson Sharif Osman Hadi....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 01:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/6061ccd941dbf6531d0e24472865f487_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Political parties protest at US aggression on Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/287216/political-parties-protest-at-us-aggression-on-venezuela</link>
      <description>Various political parties on Sunday held rallies in Dhaka protesting the American aggression against Venezuela....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 01:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/41bf419debf06db813cbbafe48012a98_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DU holds condolence meeting on life, work of Khaleda Zia</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/287215/du-holds-condolence-meeting-on-life-work-of-khaleda-zia</link>
      <description>Dhaka University on Sunday held a condolence meeting commemorating the life and works of former prime minister Khaleda Zia at the Nabab Nawab Ali Chowdhury Senate Building....Political biography book</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 01:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/87145afea740642dddfc2c836ca7476e_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICT keeps plea for foreign lawyers for Salman, Anisul on record</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/287214/ict-keeps-plea-for-foreign-lawyers-for-salman-anisul-on-record</link>
      <description>The International Crimes Tribunal-1 on Sunday kept on record the petitions filed by former prime minister’s adviser Salman F Rahman and former law minister Anisul Huq seeking permission to appoint foreign lawyers to defend them in a crimes against humanity......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202601/53cdc94b0fc981cfa67c3f439fdf0523_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
