<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed</title>
    <link>https://www.newagebd.net</link>
    <description>Daily Feed - New Age BD</description>
    <item>
      <title>Western feminists’ silence over abuse of Palestinians in Israeli prisons condemned</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/foreign-affairs/289968/western-feminists-silence-over-abuse-of-palestinians-in-israeli-prisons-condemned</link>
      <description>Sixty-eight Bangladeshi women rights activists have condemned the silence and complicity of mainstream western feminists over sexual abuse and torture of Palestinians in Israeli prisons....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ACC grills Salman F Rahman over graft charges</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/289967/acc-grills-salman-f-rahman-over-graft-charges</link>
      <description>The Anti-Corruption Commission on Sunday interrogated former lawmaker Salman F Rahman, also vice-chairman of Beximco Group, in a case filed over allegations of embezzlement and money laundering....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/66801abda7ccfa742fe06c547c9e255c_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Khamenei says recent anti-govt protests akin to ‘coup’</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/middle-east/289966/khamenei-says-recent-anti-govt-protests-akin-to-coup</link>
      <description>Iran’s supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei said Sunday that recent anti-government protests that saw killings and vandalism were akin to ‘a coup’....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/9d965e510916d6da1e79d45ae1311df7_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jamaat amir seeks ‘yes’ vote in referendum</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/289965/jamaat-amir-seeks-yes-vote-in-referendum</link>
      <description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami amir Shafiqur Rahman on Sunday urged the voters to cast ‘yes’ vote in the upcoming referendum for resisting fascist rule in the country in the future....Bangladesh travel guides</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/ad670f1bb1922775b75683696762aa5d_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BNP opposes BNCC polls duties</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/289964/bnp-opposes-bncc-polls-duties</link>
      <description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party on Sunday objected to a proposal to involve Bangladesh National Cadet Corps students in election-related duties, voicing concern over reports that ‘peace committees’ might be formed in constituencies to maintain order on the polling day....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/6cfa9f8acb4a5b9a70fbe59ab0b573bb_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Export, import disrupted as strike cripples Ctg port</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/289963/export-import-disrupted-as-strike-cripples-ctg-port</link>
      <description>The disruption of operational activities at the Chattogram port for the second consecutive day on Sunday raised concerns among businesses over export delays, transport paralysis and losses across the supply chain, as port workers maintained their......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/3defe6c8769882921039faafd788ff70_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Editors’ Council concerned over draft media ordinances</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/289962/editors-council-concerned-over-draft-media-ordinances</link>
      <description>The Editors’ Council has expressed deep concern over the process and time for formulating the drafts of the National Media Commission Ordinance and the Broadcasting Commission Ordinance....News subscription service</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/3a1004f3a02a7560cb5b365dbc3bdba9_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surging disinformation clouds polls run-up</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/289961/surging-disinformation-clouds-polls-run-up</link>
      <description>A surge of disinformation, AI-generated images, and deepfake videos spreading political hatred across social media have marked the run-up to the 13th Jatiya Sangsad elections and the referendum on February 12  amid an apparent lack of......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/32c26cae40aa92ddf51c8a55d60bdf97_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BNP, Jamaat trade blame again</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/289960/bnp-jamaat-trade-blame-again</link>
      <description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party on Sunday accused its electoral rival of exploiting religious beliefs and sentiments during election campaigns, while the Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami alleged attacks on its women activists by rival party supporters....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/0be4f0198395122b624b57a253065080_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>200 feared dead in DR Congo landslide</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/africa/289959/200-feared-dead-in-dr-congo-landslide</link>
      <description>The Democratic Republic of Congo’s government said on Sunday it feared ‘at least 200  dead’ in a ‘massive’ landslide that struck a militia-held mine in the country’s east....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine war talks delayed to Wednesday: Zelensky</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/europe/289958/ukraine-war-talks-delayed-to-wednesday-zelensky</link>
      <description>A second round of talks between Russian, Ukrainian and US officials on a US-drafted plan to end the nearly four-year Ukraine war will begin on Wednesday, instead of on Sunday, president Volodymyr Zelensky said....Political science books</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/7f74aeff81fc1782517dc0f8c5c8aa51_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SEU hosts workshop on accreditation preparation</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/education/289957/seu-hosts-workshop-on-accreditation-preparation</link>
      <description>Southeast University in collaboration with the Bangladesh Accreditation Council has recently organised a workshop titled Preparation for Accreditation: Documentation and Evidence in Dhaka....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/d8a49bfbbbd2b552f18ab9af2d7b56d9_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Packaging promises and policy gaps</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/289917/packaging-promises-and-policy-gaps</link>
      <description>TO ACCELERATE export growth and industrial expansion, Bangladesh designates a specific sector as the ‘product of the year’ annually. The selection of paper and packaging products for 2026 is, on the surface, a timely decision. Yet the real significance of this designation will depend on whether it is accompanied by effective policy support, structural reform, and concrete......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/36cde8ea82f790f16c36bba5d78af60d_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobile phones and new landscape of crime</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/Opinion/289916/mobile-phones-and-new-landscape-of-crime</link>
      <description>THE mobile phone has travelled a long way from its original purpose as a simple communication device. Today, it functions as a gateway to education, finance, work, entertainment and social life, compressing entire systems into a single object carried in the pocket. In Bangladesh, as in much of the world, this transformation has been swift and far-reaching. Mobile......Bangladesh travel guides</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/d98cff72f9047bc4aa82860c99f47937_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Growing up tired</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/289915/growing-up-tired</link>
      <description>IN BANGLADESH today, exhaustion has become an unspoken norm among young people. It appears in exam halls, coaching centres and university classrooms, and increasingly in everyday conversation. Terms such as burnout, pressure and feeling lost are used almost casually, even by those barely out of adolescence. Yet this pervasive fatigue is often dismissed as......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/e8e54e39a8f09dd5387ad39c2149e8ed_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weaving peace and harmony</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/289914/weaving-peace-and-harmony</link>
      <description>IN A world increasingly fractured by dogma and polarisation, the observance of World Interfaith Harmony Week offers a timely opportunity to reflect on the forces that bind humanity together. For Bangladesh, this United Nations initiative is not an imported idea but a recognition of lived traditions that stretch back centuries. This deltaic land, shaped by migration......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/095c3e47e7918ebe1b1c752809ded9e2_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When training wheels come off</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/289911/when-training-wheels-come-off</link>
      <description>EVERY economic crossing has its moment of truth, the point at which momentum meets gravity. East Asia confronted that moment decades ago, when rapid industrial growth collided with rising wages, tighter trade rules and fiercer competition. Only those economies that adapted early stayed upright. Bangladesh now approaches a similar reckoning as it prepares for......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/fb3d8f9c3b7331690dee8a6d6d8833d5_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Draft media ordinances reinforce bureaucratic control</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/editorial/289909/draft-media-ordinances-reinforce-bureaucratic-control</link>
      <description>AFTER months of delay and indifference to the media reform commission’s recommendations, the interim government published draft ordinances for the National Media Commission and the Broadcast Commission on January 29, but seeking public opinion in only three days. For decades, civic groups working on media freedom have asked for an independent commission......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/f3024e3e0256b062fe487f91d581b8d0_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EC must stop religious ruse in polls campaigns</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/editorial/289907/ec-must-stop-religious-ruse-in-polls-campaigns</link>
      <description>THE religious ruse that Islamic parties keep using to curry votes questions the role of the Election Commission and the government, bringing to the fore their indolence and, perhaps, unwillingness to enforce the Political Parties and Candidates’ Code of Conduct 2025, which places a bar on the abuse of religious or racial sentiments, also online, for electoral gains. What is......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/7e9494d2c7ad74c2e4722a38dec8a094_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jamaat’s Dhaka-10 candidate’s colourful posters seized</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/289983/jamaats-dhaka-10-candidates-colourful-posters-seized</link>
      <description>The police on Sunday seized a huge number of colourful posters of the Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami’s candidate for the Dhaka-10 constituency, Jashim Uddin, from his home in the capital’s Hazaribagh area....News subscription service</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 01:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Son allegedly kills mother in Rajshahi</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/289982/son-allegedly-kills-mother-in-rajshahi</link>
      <description>A woman was allegedly killed by her drug-addicted son in Rajshahi city on Saturday night....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 01:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rajshahi-2 AB Party candidate seeks security over alleged threats</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/289981/rajshahi-2-ab-party-candidate-seeks-security-over-alleged-threats</link>
      <description>An Amar Bangladesh Party candidate contesting the national elections for the Rajshahi 2 constituency has sought administrative protection, alleging threats and attempts to obstruct his election campaign....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 01:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 more injured in electioneering clashes in Patuakhali, Noakhali</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/289980/13-more-injured-in-electioneering-clashes-in-patuakhali-noakhali</link>
      <description>At least 13 more people were injured in clash between the activists and supporters of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party-led alliance and BNP rebel candidate in Patuakhali and three more injured as an 11-Party alliance rally was attacked allegedly by......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 01:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coast Guard deployed to maintain peace, order</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/289979/coast-guard-deployed-to-maintain-peace-order</link>
      <description>Members of the Bangladesh Coast Guard have been deployed in coastal areas to maintain peace and order on the occasion of the 13th Jatiya Sangsad elections and referendum scheduled to be held on February 12....Bangladesh travel guides</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 01:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/11574c40d35a4006a09bfdcef22e1d66_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CBoBS-GSG lecture highlights France-Bangladesh ties</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/289978/cbobs-gsg-lecture-highlights-france-bangladesh-ties</link>
      <description>The Centre for Bay of Bengal Studies and the Department of Global Studies and Governance of Independent University, Bangladesh in collaboration with Marana Foundation have recently organised an academic lecture titled France and the World: Bangladesh......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 01:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/60fc862555f6bd4690735e219138c220_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 grenades, firearms recovered in Jashore</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/289977/10-grenades-firearms-recovered-in-jashore</link>
      <description>The joint force recovered a total of 10 grenades, three US made pistols, 19 rounds of bullet and three sharp weapons at Bagharpara upazila in Jashore....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 01:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Political parties urged to pledge for road safety</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/289976/political-parties-urged-to-pledge-for-road-safety</link>
      <description>Road Safety Coalition Bangladesh urged the political parties to commit for the enactment and effectively implementation of a Road Safety Law in their election manifestos announced for the 13th Jatiya Sangsad elections....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 01:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Govt secondary school employees stage protest demanding 9th pay scale</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/289975/govt-secondary-school-employees-stage-protest-demanding-9th-pay-scale</link>
      <description>A section of employees of the government secondary schools on Sunday enforced a two-hour work abstention across the country, demanding the immediate announcement of the ninth national pay scale for them....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 01:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six prison guards suspended as murder accused flees jail</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/289974/six-prison-guards-suspended-as-murder-accused-flees-jail</link>
      <description>Six prison guards have been suspended after an accused in a murder case escaped from the Brahmanbaria District Jail by impersonating another inmate....Political science books</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 01:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dhaka to sign EPA with Tokyo on Feb 6, tariff deal with Washington on Feb 9</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/foreign-affairs/289973/dhaka-to-sign-epa-with-tokyo-on-feb-6-tariff-deal-with-washington-on-feb-9</link>
      <description>Bangladesh is set to sign an economic partnership agreement with Japan on February 6 and a tariff agreement with the United States on February 9....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 01:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three railway employees suspended for taking bribe</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/289972/three-railway-employees-suspended-for-taking-bribe</link>
      <description>The Bangladesh Railway on Sunday suspended its three staff for allegedly accepting money from some passengers in exchange of allowing them to travel without tickets....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 01:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tejgaon College student’s body recovered at Jigatala</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/289971/tejgaon-college-students-body-recovered-at-jigatala</link>
      <description>A Tejgaon College student’s hanging body was recovered from his rented house in the capital’s Jigatola area....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 01:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kabita Utsab begins with hope of secular democratic country</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/literature/289970/kabita-utsab-begins-with-hope-of-secular-democratic-country</link>
      <description>The two-day Jatiya Kabita Utsab 2026 began on Sunday at the Central Shaheed Minar with the hope for a free and fair election and a democratic, non-sectarian country with good governance....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 01:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/be105b80d4419b198d69cb1d0c68090e_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ekushey book fair not just a book sale event: protesters</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/literature/289969/ekushey-book-fair-not-just-a-book-sale-event-protesters</link>
      <description>Speakers, including writers, cultural activists and publishers, stated that the Amar Ekushey Book Fair is not merely a scheduled event of the ministry of cultural affairs or a book-selling venue, but a cultural festival that embodies the consciousness of the......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 01:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/32038c883f4c5578d8e58bbab3f35803_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
