<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed</title>
    <link>https://www.newagebd.net</link>
    <description>Daily Feed - New Age BD</description>
    <item>
      <title>India forced to defend US trade deal as doubts mount</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/trade-commerce/291500/india-forced-to-defend-us-trade-deal-as-doubts-mount</link>
      <description>India is scrambling to defend a new trade deal with the United States that critics have branded as a surrender to Washington, as countries navigate the fallout from president Donald Trump’s sweeping tariffs......</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/5b5ea34d18fafad8cc7e5ce3888521c4_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dhaka Central Univ gets 1st VC, ULAB, Stamford get new VCs</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/education/291499/dhaka-central-univ-gets-1st-vc-ulab-stamford-get-new-vcs</link>
      <description>Newly established public university Dhaka Central University is getting Professor ASMA Haseeb of the Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology as its first vice-chancellor....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/9e89ab69f4b8b3b288ce09a8f3b8d9e9_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran begins military drills in Hormuz</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/middle-east/291498/iran-begins-military-drills-in-hormuz</link>
      <description>Iran’s Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps on Monday began a series of military exercises in the Strait of Hormuz, state media reported, on the eve of talks with the United States....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BNP to face fate of fascist if July charter ignored: Jamaat</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/291497/bnp-to-face-fate-of-fascist-if-july-charter-ignored-jamaat</link>
      <description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami secretary general Mia Golam Parwar on Monday warned that those set to assume power might face the fate of fascists if the July National Charter was not implemented and a new state structure not built accordingly....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/78ef03b27fd73cf225b72d7e10901fdf_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13th JS election peaceful, but irregularities found in several centres: MOSUS</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/Country/291496/13th-js-election-peaceful-but-irregularities-found-in-several-centres-mosus</link>
      <description>Manobadhikar O Somaj Unnayan Songstha (MOSUS) said on Monday that the 13th Jatiya Sangsad election was largely peaceful and festive, but irregularities were reported in several polling centres....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/d65a314add4be1956a9f0ae652e46e3d_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DU arts faculty holds 2-day medical camp</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/291495/du-arts-faculty-holds-2-day-medical-camp</link>
      <description>The Faculty of Arts of Dhaka University organised a two-day medical camp at the Shaheed Mofazzal Haider Chowdhury conference room with the support of the Popular Diagnostic Centre....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/abd901cbe24488775cf7e16b6c911ae7_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarique holds courtesy meeting with IAB chief</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/291494/tarique-holds-courtesy-meeting-with-iab-chief</link>
      <description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party chairman Tarique Rahman on Monday held a courtesy meeting with Islami Andolan Bangladesh amir Syed Muhammad Rezaul Karim at the latter’s residence on Siddheswari Road in the capital Dhaka....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/9021b1e46e42dc50266bd737934be27e_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israeli approval of West Bank land registration draws outrage</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/middle-east/291493/israeli-approval-of-west-bank-land-registration-draws-outrage</link>
      <description>Israel’s government has approved a process to register land in the West Bank as ‘state property’, drawing condemnation from Arab nations and critics who said it would accelerate annexation of the Palestinian territory....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/b8ee5f461431a9847656a95b4ed589f4_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MPs’ reform council oath hinges on constitutional procedure: Salahuddin</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/291492/mps-reform-council-oath-hinges-on-constitutional-procedure-salahuddin</link>
      <description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party standing committee member Salahuddin Ahmed said on Monday that BNP lawmakers’ oath as members of the Constitutional Reform Council would depend on formal constitutional procedures....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/92227c6ed7410b3ff0692ffee33cceaa_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Businesspeople keep dominating new JS</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/291491/businesspeople-keep-dominating-new-js</link>
      <description>The 13th Jatiya Sangsad is going to be dominated by the business community as usual, with around 60 per cent of all lawmakers being businesspeople, said the Transparency International Bangladesh on Monday based on an analysis of individual affidavits....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/7c0221c1a9ef0779a391e019caae89aa_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BNP forms new govt today</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/291490/bnp-forms-new-govt-today</link>
      <description>After a gap of two decades, the Bangladesh Nationalist Party would form a new government today following separate oath-taking ceremonies of the newly elected lawmakers and members of the new cabinet....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/dd39b7299fe25668b29a99f84152b530_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India hosts AI summit as safety concerns grow</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/telecom/291489/india-hosts-ai-summit-as-safety-concerns-grow</link>
      <description>A global artificial intelligence summit kicked off in New Delhi on Monday with big issues on the agenda, from job disruption to child safety, although some attendees warned the broad focus could make concrete commitments from world leaders less likely......</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/44c8ad2df333c7c508942ba3e1217777_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards a global chaos</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/291472/towards-a-global-chaos</link>
      <description>IN THE halls of the Pentagon, a document on national defence strategy has been published that might one day be seen as starting point to end the American century. The US National Defence Strategy, unveiled in January 2026, is sold as a necessary dose of ‘hard-nosed realism.’ Proponents of the strategy claim that it will free America of the burdens of global policing......</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/82db54f4eb73178ff584e51318801725_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dhaka’s geopolitical test</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/291471/dhakas-geopolitical-test</link>
      <description>POLITICAL scientist Nicholas John Spykman observed that geography does not argue; it simply exists. The remark remains instructive. Geography imposes structural realities that states must navigate rather than debate. In a period marked by renewed great-power rivalry, these realities are again shaping strategic choices across the Indo-Pacific. As global politics......</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/591f391223ff64daf32c4d0504e4588b_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An immediate priority</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/291469/an-immediate-priority</link>
      <description>RAMADAN is here. Keeping prices affordable for ordinary people must be the government’s immediate priority. In Ramadan, family expenses naturally increase. People buy more rice, edible oil, sugar, lentils, dates, meat, eggs, fruit and other goods, but their income does not increase. According to the Bureau of Statistics, the overall inflation stood at 8.58 per cent in......</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/ae936c8148643abd044f141de228d7e6_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BNP’s economic test</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/291465/bnps-economic-test</link>
      <description>JOBLESS growth defined much of Bangladesh’s recent past. Output expanded on paper, yet secure employment did not keep pace. That paradox unfolded under an increasingly authoritarian order that, by the end, relied more on coercion than consent. The fall of that regime came at a grave human cost. Hundreds lost their lives in the turmoil that preceded......</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/157f7a738617580d2c321ae8ecbf44ae_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corruption in road development projects must end</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/editorial/291463/corruption-in-road-development-projects-must-end</link>
      <description>ROAD construction and maintenance remain among the most persistent area of corruption and governance failure. The issue of negligent planning and faulty construction returned to public attention when a stretch of a newly constructed road on the west bank of the River Turag near Kashimpur in Gazipur collapsed. Local residents said that the construction of the road......</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/4992cec38fb322ecf4fbfd9d89f796b6_medium.png" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Illiberal currents and crossroads for progressive politics</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/editorial/291462/illiberal-currents-and-crossroads-for-progressive-politics</link>
      <description>THE unprecedented share of votes secured by right-wing political parties in the national elections presents a series of urgent questions for progressive political forces about strategy, engagement and the trajectory of politics. Election Commission figures show that the Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami has secured 31.76 per cent of the total vote, a historic high, and won......</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/f03b1fe29221fc7a99094482acf81fc9_medium.png" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fire at Karwan Bazar brought under control, no casualties</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/291519/fire-at-karwan-bazar-brought-under-control-no-casualties</link>
      <description>A fire that broke out at a wood shop and spread to nearby buildings in Karwan Bazar late Monday night was brought under control early Tuesday, the Fire Service and Civil Defense said. No casualties have been reported....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 02:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DUET partners with Malaysian university</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/education/291518/duet-partners-with-malaysian-university</link>
      <description>The Dhaka University of Engineering and Technology of Gazipur and Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia have signed a memorandum of understanding recently....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rajshahi edn board suspends staff regularisation amid controversy</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/291517/rajshahi-edn-board-suspends-staff-regularisation-amid-controversy</link>
      <description>The Board of Intermediate and Secondary Education, Rajshahi on Monday suspended a process to regularise 60 lower grade employees on allegations that the recruitment was carried out without public advertisement and in violation of rules....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Imam assaulted at Kumarkhali</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/291516/imam-assaulted-at-kumarkhali</link>
      <description>A mosque imam, who is also reportedly associated with Islami Chhatra Shibir, was allegedly assaulted by unidentified individuals while returning home after evening prayers in Kumarkhali upazila of Kushtia district....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man held for rape attempt</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/291515/man-held-for-rape-attempt</link>
      <description>A man was arrested early Monday on charge of his attempt to rape a Class VI girl at Rajnagar upazila in Moulvibazar....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nepal launches campaigns for first post-uprising polls</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/south-asia/291514/nepal-launches-campaigns-for-first-post-uprising-polls</link>
      <description>Nepali candidates launched campaigning on Monday for next month’s parliamentary elections, the first since deadly anti-corruption protests toppled the previous government in 2025....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ACC sues ASP, wife over illegal wealth</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/291513/acc-sues-asp-wife-over-illegal-wealth</link>
      <description>Rajshahi Anti-Corruption Commission on Monday filed a case against a police officer and his wife on charges of concealing asset information and accumulating wealth beyond their known sources of income....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>73 fishermen brought back from Arakan Army custody</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/291512/73-fishermen-brought-back-from-arakan-army-custody</link>
      <description>The Border Guard Bangladesh on Monday brought back 73 fishermen, including six Rohingyas, from the custody of Myanmar’s rebel group Arakan Army....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/8ded4d7925e1a1d96e1e8f973bab7b58_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 rescued while being trafficked to Malaysia</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/291511/15-rescued-while-being-trafficked-to-malaysia</link>
      <description>A total of 15 people, including women and children, were rescued in a joint operation by the Bangladesh Coast Guard and Rapid Action Battalion at Teknaf’s Baharchhara area while being held captive for trafficking to Malaysia....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/c55ff8e2a73c7d52b42c2606f9012d7b_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Import stable, prices mixed</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/commodities/291510/import-stable-prices-mixed</link>
      <description>Imports of essential commodities have increased significantly ahead of Ramadan, although prices of several key items have shown a mixed trend at the wholesale markets in Dhaka and Chattogram......</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/88ff3bb289f04235eddab4f58b318093_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BB officers allege rush to grant digital bank licence</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/banking/291509/bb-officers-allege-rush-to-grant-digital-bank-licence</link>
      <description>Bangladesh Bank Officers’ Welfare Council on Monday alleged that governor Ahsan H Mansur had moved hastily to grant a digital bank licence before the elected government has been sworn in......</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/04bdeb2b18b78bc928c3a2e3a5f8aeff_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Women leadership shines amid patriarchy: discussion</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/291508/women-leadership-shines-amid-patriarchy-discussion</link>
      <description>Women leadership shines in Bengal amid patriarchy politics and economy, said academics and activists at an event on Monday....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/f36d6c0e244e0c6c6db0ad40e794c9b7_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dhaka stocks dip after surge</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/stocks/291507/dhaka-stocks-dip-after-surge</link>
      <description>Dhaka stocks declined on Monday after a surge in the previous day as a section of investors went for profit booking......</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/a5709fd074f32112f3eaf18a1955cd81_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TCB to sell Ramadan essentials from today</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/commodities/291506/tcb-to-sell-ramadan-essentials-from-today</link>
      <description>The Trading Corporation of Bangladesh will start selling key essential commodities at subsidised prices in nine metropolitan areas from Tuesday, that is today, ahead of the holy month of Ramadan......</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/2c42d3be4692ff69624f9bc49ee87434_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jibanananda Das birth anniv today</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/literature/291505/jibanananda-das-birth-anniv-today</link>
      <description>Today is the 127th anniversary of birth of one of the greatest poets of Bangla literature Jibanananda Das....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/522432b3155b482a64282e75fbb45560_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gas crisis hits Narayanganj industrial zone</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/power-energy/291504/gas-crisis-hits-narayanganj-industrial-zone</link>
      <description>Textile mills and other factories at Bhulta, Gausia and Araihazar areas of the Narayanganj industrial hub have been experiencing a severe gas crisis since Monday morning, according to industry insiders......</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/3c4db718173ac27b88be5755cda6ac83_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Former Ukraine energy minister named suspect in laundering probe</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/europe/291503/former-ukraine-energy-minister-named-suspect-in-laundering-probe</link>
      <description>Ukraine’s former energy minister German Galushchenko has been formally named as a suspect in a high-profile money laundering probe, investigators said Monday....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/5ce2c02491971232e5637cacf67f8b4e_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate change cuts hilsa haul, raising long-term supply risks</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/mis/291502/climate-change-cuts-hilsa-haul-raising-long-term-supply-risks</link>
      <description>Bangladesh’s hilsa catch is shrinking at an alarming pace as rising temperatures, erratic rainfall and shifting river flows disrupt breeding cycles, threatening supplies of the country’s national fish and a key source of income for thousands of fishermen......</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/37cae3f935cde047454596f9058a29e6_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PKSF, WB sign $150.75m deal to promote youth entrepreneurship</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/trade-commerce/291501/pksf-wb-sign-15075m-deal-to-promote-youth-entrepreneurship</link>
      <description>The Palli Karma-Sahayak Foundation and the World Bank on Monday signed a $150.75 million agreement to enhance skills development and employment opportunities for the country’s youth......</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202602/6c8961b530f69e7ec39420f76ef5c99c_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
