<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed</title>
    <link>https://www.newagebd.net</link>
    <description>Daily Feed - New Age BD</description>
    <item>
      <title>River erosion sparks alarm in Kushtia</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/285869/river-erosion-sparks-alarm-in-kushtia</link>
      <description>RESIDENTS of Kumarakhali municipality in Kushtia are gripped by fear as rapid riverbank erosion along the River Gorai threatens homes, farmland, and local infrastructure of this densely populated area....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/a1ede0d300ab447df89c52de86ad044f_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NSU presents Fall 2025 ARC Year Exhibition</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/campus-bites/285868/nsu-presents-fall-2025-arc-year-exhibition</link>
      <description>The department of architecture at North South University began the five-day Fall 2025 ARC Year Exhibition at the NSU Exhibition Hall in Dhaka on Sunday....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/ff49b694d60f37faa8ba3fa6aea4d49f_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rowa-Daw portrays hill life of Bandarban</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/photography-art-design/285867/rowa-daw-portrays-hill-life-of-bandarban</link>
      <description>Bandarban-based young visual artist Khing Shai Mong Marma’s first solo painting exhibition, titled ‘Rowa-Daw’, which portrays the hill life of Bandarban, will end today at the Ethnic Cultural Institute in Bandarban....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/35c4d39f65d08b4d7a3a2a2f2dd5b0d7_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS Community Day Bangladesh brings together over 300 cloud enthusiasts</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/Miscellany/285866/aws-community-day-bangladesh-brings-together-over-300-cloud-enthusiasts</link>
      <description>The AWS User Group Bangladesh hosted the 4th AWS Community Day Bangladesh at BRAC University’s Badda campus, bringing together more than 300 cloud professionals, developers, students, and technology enthusiasts from across the country for a day focused on learning, collaboration, and innovation recently....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/0a7797b6554d3808ae2f0748bfed1005_medium.jpeg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S Alam Group sued for embezzling Tk 62.43b from Janata Bank</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/285865/s-alam-group-sued-for-embezzling-tk-6243b-from-janata-bank</link>
      <description>The Anti-Corruption Commission on Sunday filed three cases against three companies of S Alam Group for taking undue benefits and embezzling of Tk 62.43 billion from Janata Bank’s Agrabad branch of Chattogram as loans....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/fa11bb93b4ad48d85bbbb4965fe36e67_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Court imposes travel ban on Hasina, 16 others</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/285864/court-imposes-travel-ban-on-hasina-16-others</link>
      <description>A Dhaka court on Sunday imposed travel ban on 17 people, including ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina and former roads and bridges minister Obaidul Quader, in a corruption case filed by the Anti-Corruption Commission....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/561b7ac95e3339853cf8599863017b4e_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Election campaign materials removed from DSCC area</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/285863/election-campaign-materials-removed-from-dscc-area</link>
      <description>All types of materials related to election campaigning for the 13th national parliament election and referendum have been removed from the Dhaka South City Corporation area....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Left leader Abdul Haque’s death anniv today</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/285862/left-leader-abdul-haques-death-anniv-today</link>
      <description>The 30th death anniversary of eminent left leader Abdul Haque will be observed today....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/1ed81831654795c8bcfc0b050760556b_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biman launches body cameras for all airlines</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/285861/biman-launches-body-cameras-for-all-airlines</link>
      <description>Biman Bangladesh Airlines on Sunday started using body-worn cameras to monitor the baggage handling activities of every international flight arriving at the Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport in the capital.            ...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/a6761380a043270d8d7cd923edfa5e3a_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israel approves 19 new settlements in West Bank</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/middle-east/285860/israel-approves-19-new-settlements-in-west-bank</link>
      <description>Israel’s security cabinet approved the establishment of 19 new settlements in the occupied West Bank, a move the country’s far-right finance minister said on Sunday was aimed at preventing the establishment of a Palestinian state....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/fd2722f5ed3677cc97fe7d21e12c45d4_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steady rise in internet use: BBS</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/285859/steady-rise-in-internet-use-bbs</link>
      <description>There has been a steady rise in internet use in recent years as internet usage at individual level rose from 44.5 per cent in 2023 to 48.9 per cent this year....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/3ba215f14c8a7171f989a68d92bd39a4_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two more arrested amid protests against lynching Hindu youth</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/285858/two-more-arrested-amid-protests-against-lynching-hindu-youth</link>
      <description>Two more arrests have been made for their suspected involvement in the lynching of a Hindu youth in Bhaluka upazila of Mymensingh, allegedly for hurting religious sentiments by making derogatory remarks about Prophet Muhammad....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/0bb728d97048d681a2d3ce1ae0126a03_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nine airguns seized in Moulvibazar</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/285857/nine-airguns-seized-in-moulvibazar</link>
      <description>Rapid Action Battalion recovered nine airguns from an abandoned homestead at Kamalganj upazila in Moulvibazar early Sunday....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deadline to appeal against death verdict expires for Hasina, Kamal</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/285856/deadline-to-appeal-against-death-verdict-expires-for-hasina-kamal</link>
      <description>The 30-day deadline for deposed prime minister Sheikh Hasina and former home minister Asaduzzaman Khan Kamal to appeal against the death sentences awarded by the International Crimes Tribunal-1 has expired....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/96855e1c27d1fdc28d23e6087a947756_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Next govt must ensure press freedom: senior journalists</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/285855/next-govt-must-ensure-press-freedom-senior-journalists</link>
      <description>Editors and senior journalists on Sunday demanded that the next government must ensure that the media feels safe and free to carry out critical journalism for good governance....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/0ef9d02528834588f9d7208ad6c5cd18_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICT defers decision on charges against Hasina, 11 army officers to Dec 23</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/285854/ict-defers-decision-on-charges-against-hasina-11-army-officers-to-dec-23</link>
      <description>The International Crimes Tribunal-1 on Sunday deferred until December 23 its order on whether crimes against humanity charges will be framed against deposed prime minister Sheikh Hasina, former home minister Asaduzzaman Khan, her former defence adviser......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/7ccd2e901475c5768c8ce4a54ea81ecf_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kerala has abolished extreme poverty</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/285825/kerala-has-abolished-extreme-poverty</link>
      <description>ON NOVEMBER 1, the south-western Indian state of Kerala,. home to 34 million people, was declared free from extreme poverty by chief minister Pinarayi Vijayan. Kerala is one of the few places in the world to have eradicated extreme poverty, following China, which announced in 2022 that it had eradicated extreme poverty nationwide......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/f3a006042385fc0a134ce2d89874f951_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When journalism comes under attack</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/285824/when-journalism-comes-under-attack</link>
      <description>THE attack on the offices of The Daily Star and Prothom Alo, alongside harassment of veteran editor Nurul Kabir, is not merely an incident of physical violence against media institutions. It is a direct assault on the principle of press freedom and on the democratic right of citizens to receive information without fear or intimidation. When media houses are attacked for their......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/c949e2c80f7af68ad218751621255a92_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethical AI no longer optional</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/285823/ethical-ai-no-longer-optional</link>
      <description>FROM mobile banking to public services, artificial intelligence is quietly shaping decisions that affect millions of lives in Bangladesh and beyond. These systems promise speed and efficiency and in many cases they deliver exactly that. Yet without proper governance, they can also exclude, discriminate and erode public trust. As AI adoption accelerates across sectors......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/69dc16c3f671ac8f25c4b27da9cfdc5b_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reaping maximum benefits</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/285822/reaping-maximum-benefits</link>
      <description>BANGLADESH is at a crossroads in its development trajectory. The country is passing through a viable demographic dividend as nearly 65 per cent of its population fall within the working age of 15–64 years. Yet the advantages of this dividend are yet to be tapped. The question confronting policymakers is straightforward but urgent: is this demographic window opening......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/ed04f0902faf83419c731da9a5517d54_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wildlife law should be strictly enforced</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/editorial/285820/wildlife-law-should-be-strictly-enforced</link>
      <description>THERE is growing cause for concern over the steady erosion of migratory bird habitats. Experts, conservationists and administrators on December 20 discussed urgent measures to protect migratory birds from mounting threats such as pollution, habitat loss and illegal hunting. Organised by the Nature and Biodiversity Conservation Forum, the workshop, Way Forward for......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/85daf2167dbcce8ed012b4482968e270_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elections only way out of governance mess</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/editorial/285818/elections-only-way-out-of-governance-mess</link>
      <description>THE string of arson attacks taking place on Election Commission offices outside Dhaka, cultural organisations in Dhaka and elsewhere, newspaper houses in Dhaka and their offices in outlying districts and even private houses appears not to be isolated. The surge in such incidents came about by exploiting the tragic murder of Sharif Osman Hadi, a noted face of the......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/724e7529739de7c2a3db18fa071f1d1a_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thai border clashes displace half a million: Cambodia</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/south-asia/285877/thai-border-clashes-displace-half-a-million-cambodia</link>
      <description>More than half a million people in Cambodia have been displaced by two weeks of deadly border clashes with neighbouring Thailand, Phnom Penh said Sunday, ahead of regional talks aimed at easing tensions....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 01:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine battles attempted Russian breakthrough in border region</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/europe/285876/ukraine-battles-attempted-russian-breakthrough-in-border-region</link>
      <description>The Ukrainian army was battling an attempted Russian breakthrough in the Sumy region, it said on Sunday, following reports that Moscow forcibly moved 50 people from a border village there....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 01:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU supporting 7 citizen election observer groups</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/foreign-affairs/285875/eu-supporting-7-citizen-election-observer-groups</link>
      <description>The European Union has said it is supporting seven Bangladeshi citizen election observer organisations as part of its efforts to promote free, fair and participatory elections and strengthen public trust in the electoral process ahead of the country’s......</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 01:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarique urges unity of pro-democracy parties</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/285874/tarique-urges-unity-of-pro-democracy-parties</link>
      <description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party acting chairman Tarique Rahman on Sunday called upon all political parties that believe in democracy, including the BNP, to remain united in the interest of safeguarding the country’s democratic future....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 01:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/5a3473d04cf021f66eef2e893afcb9a8_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BSF member detained in Lalmonirhat for intrusion</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/285873/bsf-member-detained-in-lalmonirhat-for-intrusion</link>
      <description>The Border Guard Bangladesh detained a constable of India’s Border Security Force for entering Bangladesh territory illegally through the Dahagram-Angarpota border at Patgram upazila in Lalmonirhat district early Sunday....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 01:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ex-Jhalakati mayor from AL arrested</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/285872/ex-jhalakati-mayor-from-al-arrested</link>
      <description>Former Jhalokathi municipality mayor Afzal Hossain Rana was arrested in the district town while he was going to the deputy commissioner’s office to renew his firearm licence....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 01:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hop Lun launches Foundation to Future</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/285871/hop-lun-launches-foundation-to-future</link>
      <description>Leading global apparel manufacturer Hop Lun has officially launched ‘Foundation to Future’, an education sponsorship programme aimed at helping workers resume their learning journey and build skills beyond the workplace....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 01:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/5be782c45fd69cd301b93f749bd1e729_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 more die of dengue, 194 fresh cases</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/285870/2-more-die-of-dengue-194-fresh-cases</link>
      <description>Health officials on Sunday said that they recorded 194 fresh cases of dengue onslaughts, killing at least two persons in the past 24 hours....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 01:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
