<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed</title>
    <link>https://www.newagebd.net</link>
    <description>Daily Feed - New Age BD</description>
    <item>
      <title>Travel ban imposed on BNP MP nominee Jalal, family</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/285947/travel-ban-imposed-on-bnp-mp-nominee-jalal-family</link>
      <description>A Dhaka Senior Special Judge’s Court on Monday issued an international travel ban on Md Jalal Uddin, the Bangladesh Nationalist Party nominated lawmaker candidate for Chandpur-2 constituency in the next general election, over allegations of acquiring illegal wealth......</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FY27 budget at Tk 8.5 lakh crore likely</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/285946/fy27-budget-at-tk-85-lakh-crore-likely</link>
      <description>The size of the national budget for the 2026-27 financial year is likely to be about Tk 8.50 lakh crore with 6 per cent growth in the gross domestic product....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/9c20c44a21cf5b577ca1552a114a0d7e_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Law, order to improve as polls day nears: CEC</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/285944/law-order-to-improve-as-polls-day-nears-cec</link>
      <description>Chief election commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin on Monday said that the country’s law and order would steadily improve as the Jatiya Sangsad elections day would approach....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/af290df73dac3002f4d28d045a3900bf_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Consonancy of Fantasy’ presents Ctg-based artists’ works in Dhaka</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/photography-art-design/285935/consonancy-of-fantasy-presents-ctg-based-artists-works-in-dhaka</link>
      <description>Five Chattogram-based contemporary artists displayed their artworks at a group art exhibition titled ‘Consonancy of Fantasy’, which is under way at Safiuddin Shilpalay of Dhanmondi in the capital....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/0e24cff085b80c615702db4b315d53d0_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peacekeepers and cost of global responsibility</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/285902/peacekeepers-and-cost-of-global-responsibility</link>
      <description>...</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/c3beaa4c4c720cab7e48c5c281e9ae7c_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hadi’s death and architecture of recycled betrayal</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/285901/hadis-death-and-architecture-of-recycled-betrayal</link>
      <description>I GREW up in the tangled alleys of thana shahar, where authority whispered rather than roared, arriving in delays, evasions and the quiet shrug of officials who assumed tomorrow would look like today. In the Navy, I learned the opposite: hesitation at the top does not calm a system — it destabilises it. Ships do not sink because of storms alone; they sink when command......</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/49b6224113202c46db31f3379ac4dc54_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Future of RMG labour</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/285900/future-of-rmg-labour</link>
      <description>IN BANGLADESH, the collapse of Rana Plaza in 2013 is remembered as a black day, and the tragedy continues to haunt those who survived it. Before engaging with the study of human rights, I too viewed the collapse largely as an accident, a catastrophic failure of a building that should never have housed factories. Over time, however, my understanding changed......</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/7d1954137ce623e8b7f62c130fd07cfb_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Symptoms of sick society, failed governance</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/285899/symptoms-of-sick-society-failed-governance</link>
      <description>THE killing of Dipu Chandra Das at Bhaluka in Mymensingh on December 18, followed by the public burning of his body, once again marks a moral nadir that should shame a nation. The young man, an employee of a local apparel factory, was beaten to death by what appears to be an organised mob. After killing the young man, the mob dragged his body to the......</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/87f92eb4c22deb5ebedaf7e6cf54540d_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internet access still beyond reach for many worrying</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/editorial/285898/internet-access-still-beyond-reach-for-many-worrying</link>
      <description>THE latest Bureau of Statistics update puts the number of households with internet connections at 56.2 per cent, which suggests that 43.8 per cent of households are still excluded from internet connectivity. This paints a bleak picture, as the ICT Access and Use Survey 2025–26 considers a household to be using the internet only if at least one person in that household uses......</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/77bae0ede64db143345393728ce4d6e2_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No measures to address heat stress in factories</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/editorial/285897/no-measures-to-address-heat-stress-in-factories</link>
      <description>HEAT stress in factories and at workplaces has increasingly become a threat to health and productivity, inflicting substantial economic losses. Yet, the issue remains largely absent from serious policy debate. A recent study by Cornell University’s Global Labour Institute warns that failure to invest in climate adaptation could cost Bangladesh about $27 billion in garment......</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/bf7322dc5ef9183171c4d31018765696_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bangladesh ethnosports team shines bright in Turkey</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/Others/285955/bangladesh-ethnosports-team-shines-bright-in-turkey</link>
      <description>The Bangladesh Ethnosport team secured third place at the Togyzqumalaq and Mangala Asian Cup 2025, held in Ankara, Turkey, from December 16 to 22, says a press release.
...</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 02:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/107b53270993fba1f7381e2d52656477_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moscow car blast kills Russian general as Ukraine peace talks stall</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/europe/285954/moscow-car-blast-kills-russian-general-as-ukraine-peace-talks-stall</link>
      <description>A car bomb killed a senior Russian general in southern Moscow on Monday morning as officials reported ‘slow progress’ in talks with the United States on how to end the war in Ukraine....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 01:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/62775f4248d7ba0ee2c07c6a2ed65454_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bangladeshi youth injured in BSF firing</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/285953/bangladeshi-youth-injured-in-bsf-firing</link>
      <description>A Bangladeshi youth was injured in the firing by Indian Border Security Force along the Daikhawa border in Hatibandha upazila of Lalmonirhat district on Monday morning....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 01:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ahasanul Huda dissolves his party, joins BNP</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/285952/ahasanul-huda-dissolves-his-party-joins-bnp</link>
      <description>Bangladesh Jatiya Dal chairman Syed Ahasanul Huda on Monday dissolved his party and joined the Bangladesh Nationalist Party with his party leaders and activists....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 01:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ACC prosecutes ex-NBL MDs, 29 others</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/285951/acc-prosecutes-ex-nbl-mds-29-others</link>
      <description>The Anti-Corruption Commission on Monday filed a case against 31 people, including former National Bank managing directors MA Wadud and Chowdhury Mustak Ahmed, on charges of embezzling Tk 647 crore....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 01:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/bfb227a0522843b10a0c708b9259d39d_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICT prosecution seeks to frame charges against Salman, Anisul</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/285950/ict-prosecution-seeks-to-frame-charges-against-salman-anisul</link>
      <description>The prosecution of the International Crimes Tribunal on Monday prayed for framing crimes against humanity charges against deposed prime minister Sheikh Hasina’s industries affairs adviser Salman F Rahman and former law minister......</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 01:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/51f60a5a07ceeb5d87abd0e50073ed4f_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israel demolishes east Jerusalem building, evicting Palestinians</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/middle-east/285949/israel-demolishes-east-jerusalem-building-evicting-palestinians</link>
      <description>Israeli bulldozers tore through a four-storey building in east Jerusalem on Monday, leaving scores of Palestinian residents unsure where to go after their doors were broken down in the middle of the night by authorities enforcing hasty evictions....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 01:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/a41aa05309a19a3adde5ad25c35fefd4_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TARIQUE RETURN: Railway cancels 3 regular trains as BNP hires special trains</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/285948/tarique-return-railway-cancels-3-regular-trains-as-bnp-hires-special-trains</link>
      <description>The Bangladesh Railway on Monday has cancelled the scheduled journeys of three trains on December 25 as it would use the trains to carry Bangladesh Nationalist Party leaders and activists on the occasion of the party’s leader Tarique Rahman’s homecoming....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 01:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/default-md.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
