<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed</title>
    <link>https://www.newagebd.net</link>
    <description>Daily Feed - New Age BD</description>
    <item>
      <title>Cambodia, Thailand declare truce</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/asia/286411/cambodia-thailand-declare-truce</link>
      <description>Thailand and Cambodia agreed to an ‘immediate’ ceasefire on Saturday, the two countries said in a joint statement, pledging to end border clashes that killed dozens of people......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/69ba815dadca1bdb8d706103f6ea9c3a_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shahbagh blockade continues for justice for Osman Hadi</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286410/shahbagh-blockade-continues-for-justice-for-osman-hadi</link>
      <description>Leaders and activists of Inquilab Mancha, along with general students and public, blocked Shahbagh for second consecutive day on Saturday, demanding justice for Sharif Osman Bin Hadi, who died on December 18 after a shooting attack days earlier......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/2e563d3ba3c8f97b81f4896e3fa29cba_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No media reform resented</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286409/no-media-reform-resented</link>
      <description>Senior journalists of the country expressed frustration over what they called the interim government’s inertia over media reform, which was crucial to the country’s democratic transition......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/763fd19964b02d7d123dd05476cff4d2_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thakurgaon shrine attacked</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286408/thakurgaon-shrine-attacked</link>
      <description>A shrine was vandalised allegedly by some unidentified miscreants in Thakurgaon town early Saturday, prompting tensions among the local residents and devotees......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/5e9a2a340d8ad6812ec7e563ab93aa03_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doc forgery intensifies visa difficulties</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286407/doc-forgery-intensifies-visa-difficulties</link>
      <description>Outbound travellers and aspiring migrant workers from Bangladesh are facing growing difficulties in securing visas to popular destinations across the world over the past year amid allegations of using forged documents in many cases......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/914047a5499ecf6ec81bed91f67c7ef0_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Division deepens in NCP</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286406/division-deepens-in-ncp</link>
      <description>National Citizen Party senior joint member secretary Tasnim Jara resigned from the party on Saturday evening, bringing to the fore sharp and entrenched internal divisions over the party leadership’s push to forge an election-centric alliance with the Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/cd38a3d35c74666b1c4843ad677a9057_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dense fog disrupts communications</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286405/dense-fog-disrupts-communications</link>
      <description>Road and air communications were disrupted on Saturday due to dense fog as eight Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport-bound flights were diverted and a bus-truck collision on the Dhaka-Mawa expressway left at least 10 people injured......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/d6017b85f11b1fa797991a7295e52c7d_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BPC profit surges on falling global oil prices</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/power-energy/286404/bpc-profit-surges-on-falling-global-oil-prices</link>
      <description>Profits by the state-owned Bangladesh Petroleum Corporation have continued to increase on the back of falling prices of petroleum fuel oils on the global market......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/22360e26845b277bd47c850188fb7b91_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bangladeshi investment abroad surges in July-Sept</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/economy/286403/bangladeshi-investment-abroad-surges-in-july-sept</link>
      <description>Net foreign direct investment outflows from Bangladesh have risen sharply, as domestic firms increasingly invest abroad......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/08b2fd04466bbbc3b70576a490dcc048_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apartment sale slump as high interest rates, uncertainty grips market</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/economy/286402/apartment-sale-slump-as-high-interest-rates-uncertainty-grips-market</link>
      <description>Bangladesh’s apartment and property sales have been declining over the past few years due to political instability, economic uncertainty, and high inflation and bank interest rates......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/d79c3b91ee16bed3cc9814dda5ad6490_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RMG sector hits green milestone with 38 LEED certified factories in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/apparel/286401/rmg-sector-hits-green-milestone-with-38-leed-certified-factories-in-2025</link>
      <description>Bangladesh’s ready-made garment industry reached a milestone in sustainable manufacturing, securing 38 new United States Green Building Council’s Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design certifications in 2025......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/bd9ee5e36f5447f3d005f194205f6017_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revenue pressure, reforms, unrest put NBR at crossroads in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/economy/286400/revenue-pressure-reforms-unrest-put-nbr-at-crossroads-in-2025</link>
      <description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) ended 2025 at the centre of Bangladesh’s growing fiscal challenge, struggling to raise higher revenue in a slowing economy while attempting long-promised reforms of a tax system criticised for inefficiency, discretion and a narrow base......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/522f8d86d35a8e973c7b60061e91f06f_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No immediate funds for merged bank depositors, BB clarifies</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/banking/286399/no-immediate-funds-for-merged-bank-depositors-bb-clarifies</link>
      <description>Depositors of the five banks currently undergoing a merger will have to wait longer to withdraw their funds......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/432fce0f78f4dbbf8673dbf09c3a435c_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Move underway to ensure 20% power subsidy for fisheries: Adviser Farida</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/Miscellany/286398/move-underway-to-ensure-20-power-subsidy-for-fisheries-adviser-farida</link>
      <description>The government is working to extend a 20 percent electricity subsidy to the fisheries sector, similar to the incentive currently enjoyed by agriculture, Fisheries and Livestock Adviser Farida Akhter said on Saturday......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/ec2fd9f5d8c9f3c6a54bef9c71b6fe4e_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Move underway to ensure 20% power subsidy for fisheries: Adviser Farida</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/mis/286398/move-underway-to-ensure-20-power-subsidy-for-fisheries-adviser-farida</link>
      <description>The government is working to extend a 20 percent electricity subsidy to the fisheries sector, similar to the incentive currently enjoyed by agriculture, Fisheries and Livestock Adviser Farida Akhter said on Saturday......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/6792a1b500a230ddccbcbe3a2aaef89f_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Final stage of transferring accounts into Sammilito Islami Bank</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/banking/286397/final-stage-of-transferring-accounts-into-sammilito-islami-bank</link>
      <description>The process of transferring the bank accounts of depositors of the five banks included under the merger to the newly formed Sammilito Islami Bank is at the final stage......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/bb7de7c3d97d0cbbdd2aba6869681b0b_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lebanon’s cabinet approves draft law on financial crisis losses</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/economy/286396/lebanons-cabinet-approves-draft-law-on-financial-crisis-losses</link>
      <description>Lebanon’s government on Friday approved a draft law to distribute financial losses from the 2019 economic crisis that deprived many Lebanese of their deposits despite strong opposition from political and banking officials......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/613ff52f37c48491b5d8b000da00049a_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From backbone to steady decline; Bangladesh’s jute exports plunge</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/agriculture/286395/from-backbone-to-steady-decline-bangladeshs-jute-exports-plunge</link>
      <description>Once hailed as the golden fiber and the backbone of Bangladesh’s post-independence economy, jute now contributes less than 2% to the country’s total export earnings, a sharp fall from nearly 90% in the 1970s......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/df7d9892b2433096f773370caed1adf1_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mustard cultivation exceeds target in Dinajpur, expecting bumper yield</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/agriculture/286394/mustard-cultivation-exceeds-target-in-dinajpur-expecting-bumper-yield</link>
      <description>Mustard cultivation in the district has exceeded the target set by the Department of Agricultural Extension (DAE) this season, raising hopes for a bumper harvest and increased edible oil production......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/de2d2bdc66c0bccdf6644336aa253780_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US air traffic snarled as New York braces for deep snow</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/mis/286393/us-air-traffic-snarled-as-new-york-braces-for-deep-snow</link>
      <description>Airlines canceled 1,500 US flights during the peak holiday travel period Friday, with severe winter storm warnings and heavy snow forecast across parts of the Midwest and northeast......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/e07aa469d2f38a82425bf1ae6b66c1d1_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025’s top grossing mobile games so far</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/telecom/286392/2025s-top-grossing-mobile-games-so-far</link>
      <description>Mobile games continue as one of the most coveted pastimes. More people are spending time playing games on their smartphones than ever. With over 3 billion players worldwide, the mobile gaming industry is thriving. Last year’s (2024) 3 trillion gross revenue from the mobile-phone-gaming industry makes the current year even more optimistic. Let’s delve into 2025’s......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/d7557cc574c546e99e1ecfd99b43d450_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Violence and ‘democracy’</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/286365/violence-and-democracy</link>
      <description>THE technology imposed upon us is not free; it entails costs beyond the money we spend on personal purchases or the increase in public-utility bills. It becomes firmly entrenched in our lives before the realisation that people are being killed for us to have it takes hold. Just like the piano keys of the 18th century, modern tech gets cleansed of the blood long before we......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/8a5b9914196bee98a79239aac12195b8_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security of island states</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/286363/security-of-island-states</link>
      <description>IN THE geopolitical landscape of the 21st century, climate change can no longer be confined to the narrow realm of environmental protection. It has evolved into a structural global crisis whose consequences are increasingly reflected in questions of state security, sovereignty, borders and international diplomacy. Driven by unchecked carbon emissions and global......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/316566849d0bc97d8bc6de6badd28256_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Support to self-reliance</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/286360/support-to-self-reliance</link>
      <description>FOR millions of families in Bangladesh, poverty is not an abstract statistic. It is the daily reality of worrying about whether there will be enough food to eat, school fees to pay, or money for medicines. Nearly one in five Bangladeshis still lives below the national poverty line, with rural poverty exceeding urban rates and the risk of falling back into deprivation increasing......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/9d9e2df073262aba0037ea5b6dc19290_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cinema as witness to time</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/286359/cinema-as-witness-to-time</link>
      <description>CINEMA began not as a fiction, but as a document. The history of cinema is celebrated around the globe every year on December 28 and one might argue that it is done so wrongfully. When we speak of World Cinema Day, we often narrate it as the day when the first cinema was created. Similarly, when speaking of the Lumière brothers, they are often described as the......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/2fc0eda1de5a4c1b084de95918e7a848_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Funds that sleep</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/opinion/286358/funds-that-sleep</link>
      <description>DISASTER management fund sleeps — a senior government official with decades of expertise in the field once said. This simple, yet stinging observation captures the tragic irony of Bangladesh’s disaster management strategy. We have the vision, we have the recognition, we have the legal framework and we certainly have the need. Yet, our most critical financial.....</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/3e5ecdf29b9854a46c9d64a256144616_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issues for govt to fix to deal with surplus agricultural output</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/editorial/286357/issues-for-govt-to-fix-to-deal-with-surplus-agricultural-output</link>
      <description>A RECORD record potato harvest this season for farmers in the north has become a stark illustration of how abundance can paradoxically breed disaster. What should have been a period of relative prosperity has instead turned into a likely financial crisis as prices have plummeted to levels far below production costs. Early potatoes, expected to bring a premium before the main......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/82c6ee88c65f6e1819b83b3d405578a9_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jamaat’s ruse of religion calls for early EC, govt action</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/editorial/286356/jamaats-ruse-of-religion-calls-for-early-ec-govt-action</link>
      <description>THE Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami’s ruse of religious sentiments to curry votes in the run-up to the national elections set for February 12, as New Age reported on December 27, is troublesome. Party leaders, mainly at the grass roots, have started using religious sentiments of the Muslims in their electoral campaigns, claiming that it is the religious responsibility of the......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/39bc9f4deba4f221b60f273e067df223_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DAP amendment to increase hazard risks for Dhaka: urban planners</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286438/dap-amendment-to-increase-hazard-risks-for-dhaka-urban-planners</link>
      <description>Repeated amendments to the Detailed Area Plan for Dhaka, allegedly driven by vested quarters, would intensify civic crises and hazard risks for the city already struggling to ensure minimum liveable condition for its dwellers, urban planners said on Saturday......City &amp; Local Guides</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 04:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/0f1caa3c5f696b455a9574aca1b0bf3b_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A hope for Bawm community</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286437/a-hope-for-bawm-community</link>
      <description>A new tourist centre, Ala Mi Tlang Eco Resort, is being constructed at an altitude of about 2,100 feet above sea level at the foot of Keokradong, one of the country’s highest mountain peaks, in Susuang Para of Bandarban......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 04:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/d182ede26349e056a4eb8f4f8d6296ff_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Skills, competence key to employment: Supradip Chakma</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286436/skills-competence-key-to-employment-supradip-chakma</link>
      <description>Chittagong Hill Tracts affairs adviser Supradip Chakma on Saturday said that the youth were the country’s greatest asset, stressing that skills and competence were the main keys to employment......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 04:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/d8465a3ca06ace203ba2fbe1ab4852e3_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ansar, VDP launches countrywide medical campaign</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286435/ansar-vdp-launches-countrywide-medical-campaign</link>
      <description>The Bangladesh Ansar and Village Defence Party on Saturday launched a special nationwide free medical campaign for its members and family members as part of the force’s ongoing humanitarian and welfare-oriented activities......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 04:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/e313b80aa253fc22d77031e44a9824a6_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expatriates accorded reception in Sylhet</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286434/expatriates-accorded-reception-in-sylhet</link>
      <description>Sylhet district administration on Saturday accorded reception to more than one hundred expatriates for their contribution to Bangladesh’s economy......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 04:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/2d045a7910589f96ef41ca67d24bce0f_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teenager dies in Chandpur market fire, 5 shops gutted</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286433/teenager-dies-in-chandpur-market-fire-5-shops-gutted</link>
      <description>A 15-year-old boy died in a fire that broke out at Sahar Bazar under Faridganj in Chandpur on Saturday morning......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 04:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/4d6fbc0bfe07dc749ff88351c40e2159_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Holy Child Int’l School gives prizes</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/campus-bites/286432/holy-child-intl-school-gives-prizes</link>
      <description>The annual examination results announcement and prize distribution ceremony 2025 was held at the Holy Child International School at Mirpur in the capital on Thursday......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 04:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/f6eca189141b40f84c8306223f67c5fe_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navy arrests 11 with huge cement, diesel while smuggling to Myanmar</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286431/navy-arrests-11-with-huge-cement-diesel-while-smuggling-to-myanmar</link>
      <description>The Inter Services Public Relations in a press release on Saturday said that the Bangladesh Navy had arrested 11 ‘smugglers’, including an engine-powered boat with huge cement and diesel being smuggled to Myanmar from the Kutubdia outer anchorage area in the Bay of Bengal......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 04:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/3f73f6454e0b28958935fa75405ee16d_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Romel Rahman wins Pratidhwani Story Prize</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/literature/286430/romel-rahman-wins-pratidhwani-story-prize</link>
      <description>Writer Romel Rahman has won the 1st Pratidhwani Story Prize 2025, said a release......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 04:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/51d1cd0758cef4be753231565ecf647f_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>United International Univ holds 8th convocation</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/campus-bites/286429/united-international-univ-holds-8th-convocation</link>
      <description>The United International University held its 8th convocation on the UIU campus at the United City at Madani Avenue in Dhaka on Saturday......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 04:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/a990f8322ebfdcd51bb7876d105fafb2_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trial of attackers on Prothom Alo, Daily Star demanded</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286428/trial-of-attackers-on-prothom-alo-daily-star-demanded</link>
      <description>Journalists and photojournalists from different news media houses on Saturday protested at the recent arson attack on and vandalism and looting of Prothom Alo and The Daily Star, demanding speedy trial of the perpetrators......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 04:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/2e2eeb379057920aaa1e673d54ca0d3f_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GUB Career Expo draws top brands</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/campus-bites/286427/gub-career-expo-draws-top-brands</link>
      <description>The Internship Fair and Career Expo 2025 was held on the Green University of Bangladesh (GUB) campus on Saturday, with the slogan ‘Step into a world of endless opportunities’......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 04:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/f9ca41cbd904c2655a1e8565442e6f33_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mamun Habib gets award from Thailand</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286426/mamun-habib-gets-award-from-thailand</link>
      <description>Professor Md Mamun Habib, head of the Department of Management at Independent University, Bangladesh (IUB), has received ‘Excellence Researcher Award’ conferred by Shinawatra University of Thailand......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 04:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/c24b405cc605a57bd5a63ecc162742c2_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Youth beaten after being tied to electric pole admitted to NITOR</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286425/youth-beaten-after-being-tied-to-electric-pole-admitted-to-nitor</link>
      <description>The youth, who was beaten and hacked after being tied to an electric pole at Shibganj upazila in Chapainawabganj, has been admitted to the National Institute of Traumatology and Orthopaedic Rehabilitation in Dhaka as his condition deteriorated......City &amp; Local Guides</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 04:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/68ed160dba691489cd6e9450cd5fb53d_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JUJA celebrates 54th founding anniversary</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/campus-bites/286424/juja-celebrates-54th-founding-anniversary</link>
      <description>The Jahangirnagar University Journalists’ Association marked its 54th founding anniversary on Saturday with a series of events on campus......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 03:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/467fc1271d27dcae91f35a8f186b9f62_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BUTex plays significant role in country’s economic dev: Abrar</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/campus-bites/286423/butex-plays-significant-role-in-countrys-economic-dev-abrar</link>
      <description>Education adviser Chowdhury Rafiqul Abrar said on Saturday that the Bangladesh University of Textiles contributed to developing skilled professionals for the textile sector and was therefore playing a significant role in Bangladesh’s economic development......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 01:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/f8c66796f55db5b6af2ed05b1a32b51b_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Religious minorities want polls manifestos include their rights, safety</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286422/religious-minorities-want-polls-manifestos-include-their-rights-safety</link>
      <description>Leaders of the Bangladesh Hindu Buddhist Christian Unity Council at a discussion on Saturday called on the political parties to include issues of ensuring rights and safety of religious minorities in their election manifestos for the general elections scheduled for February 12 next year......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 01:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/bcb2269e42faac356c658f201c859766_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bangla Academy hands over awards, fellowships</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/others1/286421/bangla-academy-hands-over-awards-fellowships</link>
      <description>The 48th annual general meeting of the Bangla Academy was held on Saturday with various programmes, including a fellowship and an award ceremony......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 01:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/cc5683805e45819c148c54aa603255f7_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6.6-magnitude quake hits off Taiwan</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/asia/286420/66-magnitude-quake-hits-off-taiwan</link>
      <description>A 6.6-magnitude earthquake struck off Taiwan’s northeastern coast on Saturday, the US Geological Survey said, the second major tremor to hit the island within days......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 01:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/82ed7c77c7bcbeae67a3d5af74e975e0_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>131 more migrants rescued off southern Crete</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/europe/286419/131-more-migrants-rescued-off-southern-crete</link>
      <description>The Greek coast guard Saturday rescued 131 migrants off Crete, bringing the number of people brought out of the sea in the area over the past five days to 840, a police spokesperson said......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 01:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/911b414a5786b8814a48e2d5c53051e0_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK launches paid military gap-year scheme</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/europe/286418/uk-launches-paid-military-gap-year-scheme</link>
      <description>The United Kingdom will launch a military ‘gap year’ scheme, as part of efforts to boost recruitment and reconnect young people with defence, the government said Saturday......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 01:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/236725908d4defbd091fc11855f796d1_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spardha premiered four plays</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/theatre/286417/spardha-premiered-four-plays</link>
      <description>Spardha Academy of Performing Arts premiered four short duration stage play as a part of their extensive six- module direction course at Spardha Atelier in Gulshan 2 in the capital on Friday and Saturday......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 01:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/f865c27131a8e575d01395336ae6fdc4_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NCTB to make available all 2026 textbooks online today</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286416/nctb-to-make-available-all-2026-textbooks-online-today</link>
      <description>The National Curriculum and Textbook Board is set to upload and make all free textbooks for 2026 academic year available online today (Sunday) amid concern of not being able to distribute all the books among the students on January 1......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 01:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/fd8b8f5f4e8d9f865513fac68244402a_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BSF halts fence construction at Jaipurhat border after BGB intervention</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286415/bsf-halts-fence-construction-at-jaipurhat-border-after-bgb-intervention</link>
      <description>The Indian Border Security Force attempted to construct a barbed wire fence at the Ghonapara border under Panchbibi in Jaipurhat on Saturday morning, violating international border regulations, but was forced to stop after intervention by the Border Guard Bangladesh......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 01:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/cb40f005620c2c53fb2f2bbf0b59ff89_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NHF urges govt to promulgate tobacco control ordinance</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/miscellany/286414/nhf-urges-govt-to-promulgate-tobacco-control-ordinance</link>
      <description>The National Heart Foundation of Bangladesh on Saturday urged the government to publish the amended tobacco control ordinance in the official gazette without delay to ensure its swift and effective implementation......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 01:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/a40a1ac617187e7ea17097b858f53d85_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christmas celebrations face attacks in India</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/south-asia/286413/christmas-celebrations-face-attacks-in-india</link>
      <description>While much of the world marked Christmas with joy and public celebration, the festival passed under a cloud of fear in parts of India, as reports emerged of attacks, intimidation and disruptions targeting Christian communities across several states......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 01:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/c2d63d3856a0e950743414ad3817aeb2_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BSF pushes 14 more into Bangladesh</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286412/bsf-pushes-14-more-into-bangladesh</link>
      <description>THE Indian Border Security Force reportedly forced 14 members of an Indian family into Bangladesh through Chuadanga border on Friday night......</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://outspoken.newagebd.com/files/img/202512/b25b4c32f38f7e3d31d7bf9618834af1_medium.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
